var Questions = [
// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-1/
  {"id":"4657","question":"What are two responsibilities that you will have as a British citizen or permanent resident of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"To look after the area in which you live and the environment","correct":true},{"text":"To look after yourself and your family","correct":true},{"text":"To stay in the UK forever","correct":false},{"text":"To promote work in your local community","correct":false}],"explanation":"If you wish to be a permanent resident or citizen of the UK, you should: look after yourself and your family, look after the area in which you live and the environment, respect and obey the law, respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions and treat others with fairness."},
  {"id":"4658","question":"Where is Big Ben located?","answers":[{"text":"Buckingham Palace","correct":false},{"text":"The Tower of London","correct":false},{"text":"Trafalgar Square","correct":false},{"text":"The Houses of the Parliament","correct":true}],"explanation":"Big Ben is the nickname for the great bell of the clock at the Houses of Parliament in London."},
  {"id":"4659","question":"When were men and women given the right to vote at the age of 21?","answers":[{"text":"1918","correct":false},{"text":"1903","correct":false},{"text":"1928","correct":true},{"text":"1923","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1928, women were given the right to vote at the age of 21, the same as men."},
  {"id":"4660","question":"Where is the UK geographically located?","answers":[{"text":"South west of Europe","correct":false},{"text":"North east of Europe","correct":false},{"text":"North west of Europe","correct":true},{"text":"South east of Europe","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UK is located in the north west of Europe."},
  {"id":"4661","question":"Who is the patron Saint of Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"St David","correct":false},{"text":"St Patrick","correct":false},{"text":"St George","correct":false},{"text":"St Andrew","correct":true}],"explanation":"The patron Saint of Scotland is St Andrew."},
  {"id":"4662","question":"Which two houses fought in the Wars of the Roses?","answers":[{"text":"The House of Chester","correct":false},{"text":"The House of York","correct":true},{"text":"The House of Lancaster","correct":true},{"text":"The House of Newcastle","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Wars of the Roses were fought between the supporters of two families: the House of Lancaster and the House of York."},
  {"id":"4663","question":"The Bill of Rights of 1689 confirmed the right to vote for all adult men.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. The Bill of Rights, 1689, confirmed the rights of Parliament and the limits of the king’s power."},
  {"id":"4664","question":"What is the Cenotaph?","answers":[{"text":"A flower","correct":false},{"text":"A Christian church","correct":false},{"text":"A war memorial","correct":true},{"text":"A theatre","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Cenotaph is a war memorial and it is the site of the annual Remembrance Day service attended by the Queen, politicians and foreign ambassadors."},
  {"id":"4665","question":"Who was the first female Prime Minister of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Mary Stuart","correct":false},{"text":"Theresa May","correct":false},{"text":"Margaret Thatcher","correct":true},{"text":"Florence Nightingale","correct":false}],"explanation":"Margaret Thatcher was the first woman Prime Minister of the UK."},
  {"id":"4666","question":"Who chairs the debates at the House of Commons?","answers":[{"text":"A bishop","correct":false},{"text":"The Prime Minister","correct":false},{"text":"The Speaker","correct":true},{"text":"The archbishop of Canterbury","correct":false}],"explanation":"Debates in the House of Commons are chaired by the Speaker."},
  {"id":"4667","question":"Who was the captain of the English football team that won the World Cup in 1966?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Roger Bannister","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Jackie Stewart","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Ian Botham","correct":false},{"text":"Bobby Moore","correct":true}],"explanation":"Bobby Moore captained the English football team that won the World Cup in 1966."},
  {"id":"4668","question":"When did the English defeat the Spanish Armada?","answers":[{"text":"1466","correct":false},{"text":"1066","correct":false},{"text":"1254","correct":false},{"text":"1588","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 1588 the English defeated the Spanish Armada."},
  {"id":"4669","question":"Anyone can make a complaint about the police by writing to the Chief Constable of the police force involved.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is TRUE."},
  {"id":"4670","question":"What is the minimum age required to serve on a jury?","answers":[{"text":"16","correct":false},{"text":"18","correct":true},{"text":"21","correct":false},{"text":"25","correct":false}],"explanation":"Anyone who is on the electoral register and is aged 18 to 70 can be asked to serve on a jury."},
  {"id":"4671","question":"How is a jury selected?","answers":[{"text":"From the NHS registration system","correct":false},{"text":"Randomly from the electoral register","correct":true},{"text":"Alphabetically from the telephone directory","correct":false},{"text":"From a postcode selection","correct":false}],"explanation":"As well as getting the right to vote, people on the electoral register are randomly selected to serve on a jury. Anyone who is on the electoral register and is aged 18 to 70 can be asked to do this."},
  {"id":"4672","question":"What is a bank holiday?","answers":[{"text":"A public holiday when banks are open all day","correct":false},{"text":"A public holiday for people working in banks","correct":false},{"text":"An additional day off that every worker in the UK is entitled to","correct":false},{"text":"A public holiday when banks and many other businesses are closed for the day","correct":true}],"explanation":"There are public holidays each year called bank holidays, when banks and many other businesses are closed for the day."},
  {"id":"4673","question":"What will you be given to vote before a general election takes place?","answers":[{"text":"A poll tax relief","correct":false},{"text":"A number to queue at the polling station","correct":false},{"text":"A poll card","correct":true},{"text":"An specific time for you to vote","correct":false}],"explanation":"Before the election you will be sent a poll card."},
  {"id":"4674","question":"Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"text":"Solicitors' charges are usually based on how much time they spend on a case","correct":true},{"text":"Solicitors' charges are usually based on the nature of a case and its importance","correct":false}],"explanation":"Solicitors’ charges are usually based on how much time they spend of a case."},
  {"id":"4675","question":"By law, which TWO types of media have to give a balanced coverage of all political parties and equal time to rival viewpoints before an election?","answers":[{"text":"Television","correct":true},{"text":"Internet","correct":false},{"text":"Newspapers","correct":false},{"text":"Radio","correct":true}],"explanation":"By law, radio and television coverage of the political parties must be balanced and so equal time has to be given to rival viewpoints."},
  {"id":"4676","question":"Which of the following territories is a Crown dependency but is NOT part of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"The Channel Islands","correct":true},{"text":"Scotland","correct":false}],"explanation":"Channel Islands is a British overseas territory linked to the UK, but it is not part of it."},
  {"id":"4677","question":"What did Sir Frank Whittle invent in the 1930s?","answers":[{"text":"Radar","correct":false},{"text":"Hovercraft","correct":false},{"text":"Jet engine","correct":true},{"text":"Ballpoint pen","correct":false}],"explanation":"The jet engine was developed in Britain in the 1930s by Sir Frank Whittle."},
  {"id":"4678","question":"Who wrote ‘The Daffodils’?","answers":[{"text":"William Blake","correct":false},{"text":"Robert Browning","correct":false},{"text":"Lord Byron","correct":false},{"text":"William Wordsworth","correct":true}],"explanation":"The British poet William Wordsworth wrote ‘The Daffodils’."},
  {"id":"4679","question":"Who was given the title of Lord Protector?","answers":[{"text":"Charles I","correct":false},{"text":"Charles II","correct":false},{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":false},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":true}],"explanation":"Oliver Cromwell was given the title of Lord Protector and ruled until his death in 1658."},
  {"id":"4680","question":"What are the 40 days before Easter called?","answers":[{"text":"Diwali","correct":false},{"text":"Lent","correct":true},{"text":"Hannukah","correct":false},{"text":"Vaisakhi","correct":false}],"explanation":"The 40 days before Easter are known as Lent."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-2/
  {"id":"4681","question":"What is the Home Secretary responsible for?","answers":[{"text":"Health","correct":false},{"text":"Defence","correct":false},{"text":"Education","correct":false},{"text":"Policing","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Home Secretary is responsible for crime, policing and immigration."},
  {"id":"4682","question":"St Helena is a British overseas territory and it is part of the United Kingdom.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"British overseas territories, such as St Helena and the Falkland Islands are linked to the UK but are not part of it."},
  {"id":"4683","question":"Several Church of England bishops sit in the House of Lords.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4684","question":"When walking your dog in a public place, you must ensure:","answers":[{"text":"That your dog does not play with other dogs","correct":false},{"text":"That your dog wears a collar showing the name and address of the owner","correct":true},{"text":"That your dog wears a high visibility jacket","correct":false},{"text":"That your dog does not bark","correct":false}],"explanation":"All dogs in public places must wear a collar showing the name and address of the owner."},
  {"id":"4685","question":"Women over the age of 30 were given the right to vote as a result of their contribution towards the war effort. Which war was that?","answers":[{"text":"The Second World War","correct":false},{"text":"The Crimean War","correct":false},{"text":"The First World War","correct":true},{"text":"The Civil War","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1918, women over the age of 30 were given voting rights and the right to stand for Parliament, partly in recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the First World War."},
  {"id":"4686","question":"When did Ireland become a republic?","answers":[{"text":"1925","correct":false},{"text":"1939","correct":false},{"text":"1949","correct":true},{"text":"1927","correct":false}],"explanation":"Ireland became a republic in 1949."},
  {"id":"4687","question":"Where did the first farmers come from?","answers":[{"text":"South-west Europe","correct":false},{"text":"South-east Europe","correct":true},{"text":"North-east America","correct":false},{"text":"North-west Asia","correct":false}],"explanation":"The first farmers arrived in Britain 6,000 years ago. The ancestors of these first farmers probably came from south-east Europe."},
  {"id":"4688","question":"The National Anthem ‘God save the queen’ can only be played in the presence of the Queen.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"The National Anthem is played at important national occasions and at events attended by the Queen or the Royal Family."},
  {"id":"4689","question":"Who became Prime Minister and was an inspirational leader to the British people during WWII?","answers":[{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":true},{"text":"Clement Attlee","correct":false},{"text":"Margaret Thatcher","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Robert Walpole","correct":false}],"explanation":"Winston Churchill."},
  {"id":"4690","question":"What is the title of the Queen’s eldest son, Prince Charles?","answers":[{"text":"Prince of Kent","correct":false},{"text":"Prince of Wales","correct":true},{"text":"Prince of Hanover","correct":false},{"text":"Prince of Brunswick","correct":false}],"explanation":"Prince Charles is also known as the Prince of Wales."},
  {"id":"4691","question":"Under which king did the Anglo-Saxon kingdoms in England unite to defeat the Vikings?","answers":[{"text":"William of Orange","correct":false},{"text":"King Alfred the Great","correct":true},{"text":"Henry VIII","correct":false},{"text":"Robert the Bruce","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Anglo-Saxon kingdoms in England united under King Alfred the Great, who defeated the Vikings."},
  {"id":"4692","question":"When was the Magna Carta created?","answers":[{"text":"1514","correct":false},{"text":"1215","correct":true},{"text":"1415","correct":false},{"text":"1314","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Magna Carta was created in 1215."},
  {"id":"4693","question":"Northern Ireland has its own banknotes, which are valid everywhere in the UK.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4694","question":"Which of the following plays was written by William Shakespeare?","answers":[{"text":"Pride and Prejudice","correct":false},{"text":"A Midsummer Night’s dream","correct":true},{"text":"Sense and Sensibility","correct":false},{"text":"Great Expectations","correct":false}],"explanation":"William Shakespeare’s most famous plays include A Midsummer Night’s dream."},
  {"id":"4695","question":"How many members does a jury have in England, Wales and Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"9","correct":false},{"text":"12","correct":true},{"text":"15","correct":false},{"text":"20","correct":false}],"explanation":"In England, Wales and Northern Ireland a jury has 12 members."},
  {"id":"4696","question":"Which two of the following religious communities celebrate Diwali?","answers":[{"text":"Buddhists","correct":false},{"text":"Hindus","correct":true},{"text":"Jews","correct":false},{"text":"Sikhs","correct":true}],"explanation":"Diwali is celebrated by Hindus and Sikhs."},
  {"id":"4697","question":"What is Good Friday?","answers":[{"text":"The day when Jesus Christ rose from the dead","correct":false},{"text":"The day when Jesus Christ was born","correct":false},{"text":"The day when Jesus Christ died","correct":true},{"text":"The day when Jesus Christ became 30 years old","correct":false}],"explanation":"Good Friday marks the death of Jesus Christ during the Easter."},
  {"id":"4698","question":"St Patrick’s day is a public holiday in Northern Ireland.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"True. Only Scotland and Northern Ireland have their patron saint’s day as an official holiday (although in Scotland not all businesses and offices will close)."},
  {"id":"4699","question":"Which was the last successful foreign invasion of England that took place in 1066?","answers":[{"text":"The Viking invasion","correct":false},{"text":"The Anglo-Saxon Conquest","correct":false},{"text":"The Roman invasion","correct":false},{"text":"The Norman Conquest","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Norman Conquest was the last successful foreign invasion of England in 1066."},
  {"id":"4700","question":"Where are the Crown Jewels kept?","answers":[{"text":"At the House of Commons","correct":false},{"text":"At the Tower of London","correct":true},{"text":"At Buckingham Palace","correct":false},{"text":"At Windsor Castle","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Crown Jewels are kept at the Tower of London."},
  {"id":"4701","question":"Which sport can be traced back to the 15th century in Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"Golf","correct":true},{"text":"Tennis","correct":false},{"text":"Football","correct":false},{"text":"Rugby","correct":false}],"explanation":"The modern game of golf can be traced back to 15th century Scotland."},
  {"id":"4702","question":" Who was the first person in England to print books using a printing press?","answers":[{"text":"William Shakespeare","correct":false},{"text":"John Barbour","correct":false},{"text":"Geoffrey Chaucer","correct":false},{"text":"William Caxton","correct":true}],"explanation":"William Caxton was the first person in England to print books using a printing press."},
  {"id":"4703","question":"Which court deals with minor criminal cases in England, Wales and Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"High Court","correct":false},{"text":"Justice of the Peace Court","correct":false},{"text":"Magistrates’ Court","correct":true},{"text":"Crown Court","correct":false}],"explanation":"In England, Wales and Northern Ireland, most minor criminal cases are dealt with in a Magistrates’ Court. In Scotland, minor criminal offences go to a Justice of the Peace Court."},
  {"id":"4704","question":"What did the Scottish John Logie Baird develop?","answers":[{"text":"Television","correct":true},{"text":"Radar","correct":false},{"text":"Personal computer","correct":false},{"text":"Radio","correct":false}],"explanation":"The television was developed by Scotsman John Logie Baird in the 1920s."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-3/
  {"id":"4705","question":"Which of the following is a fundamental principle of British life?","answers":[{"text":"Communism","correct":false},{"text":"Intolerance","correct":false},{"text":"Individual liberty","correct":true},{"text":"Inequity","correct":false}],"explanation":"Individual liberty is the correct answer."},
  {"id":"4706","question":"Wales has its own established church.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. There is no established Church in Wales or Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"4707","question":"How is New Year’s Eve called in Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"Vaisakhi","correct":false},{"text":"Hannukah","correct":false},{"text":"Diwali","correct":false},{"text":"Hogmanay","correct":true}],"explanation":"In Scotland, the 31st of December (New Year’s Eve) is called Hogmanay."},
  {"id":"4708","question":"Why did Henry VIII establish the church of England?","answers":[{"text":"To celebrate his wedding with Anne of Cleves","correct":false},{"text":"To have control over religious people","correct":false},{"text":"To establish a unique religion in England","correct":false},{"text":"To divorce his first wife, Catherine of Aragon","correct":true}],"explanation":"To divorce his first wife, Henry needed the approval of the Pope. When the Pope refused, Henry established the church of England."},
  {"id":"4709","question":"What is the name of the long war that English kings fought with France in the middle ages?","answers":[{"text":"The Crimean War","correct":false},{"text":"The First World War","correct":false},{"text":"The Hundred Years War","correct":true},{"text":"The Boer War","correct":false}],"explanation":"English kings fought a long war with France, called the Hundred Years War (even though it actually lasted 116 years)."},
  {"id":"4711","question":"Who was supported by clansmen from the Scottish highlands and raised and army in 1745?","answers":[{"text":"Bonnie Prince Charlie","correct":true},{"text":"Robert Burns","correct":false},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false},{"text":"Kenneth MacAlpin","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1745 there was another attempt to put a Stuart king back on the throne in place of George I’s son, George II. Charles Edward Stuart (Bonnie Prince Charlie), the grandson of James II, landed in Scotland. He was supported by clansmen from the Scottish highlands and raised and army."},
  {"id":"4712","question":"If you think someone is trying to persuade you to join an extremist or terrorist activity, who should you contact?","answers":[{"text":"The Home Office","correct":false},{"text":"Your local police force","correct":true},{"text":"Your local MP","correct":false},{"text":"Your family","correct":false}],"explanation":"If you think someone is trying to persuade you to join an extremist or terrorist cause, you should notify your local police force."},
  {"id":"4713","question":"It is compulsory for 16 and 17-year-olds to join the National Citizen Service programme.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. The National Citizen Service programme, which gives 16- and 17-year-olds the opportunity to enjoy outdoor activities, develop their skills and take part in a community project. Therefore, it is optional."},
  {"id":"4710","question":"What is the name of the tour guides that tell visitors stories about the Tower of London’s history?","answers":[{"text":"Knights","correct":false},{"text":"Chartists","correct":false},{"text":"Suffragettes","correct":false},{"text":"Beefeaters","correct":true}],"explanation":"Tours are given at the Tower of London by the Yeoman Warders, also known as Beefeaters, who tell visitors about the building’s history."},
  {"id":"4714","question":"Which two countries developed the Concorde, the world’s only supersonic commercial airliner?","answers":[{"text":"Italy","correct":false},{"text":"Britain","correct":true},{"text":"Germany","correct":false},{"text":"France","correct":true}],"explanation":"Britain and France developed the world’s only supersonic commercial airliner, Concorde."},
  {"id":"4715","question":"Where is Snowdonia located?","answers":[{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":true},{"text":"England","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false}],"explanation":"Snowdonia is in Wales."},
  {"id":"4716","question":"Who wrote Sherlock Holmes?","answers":[{"text":"Evelyn Waugh","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Kingsley Amis","correct":false},{"text":"Graham Greene","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Arthur Conan Doyle","correct":true}],"explanation":"Sir Arthur Conan Doyle is the author of Sherlock Holmes."},
  {"id":"4717","question":"Which country was invaded by Germany in 1939?","answers":[{"text":"Austria","correct":false},{"text":"Italy","correct":false},{"text":"Russia","correct":false},{"text":"Poland","correct":true}],"explanation":"Germany invaded Poland in 1939."},
  {"id":"4718","question":"Who is the patron Saint of Wales?","answers":[{"text":"St David","correct":true},{"text":"St George","correct":false},{"text":"St Patrick","correct":false},{"text":"St Andrew","correct":false}],"explanation":"The patron Saint of Wales is St David."},
  {"id":"4719","question":"Lake District is the largest national park of England.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4720","question":"What is the name of the area in London where famous theatres are located?","answers":[{"text":"Soho","correct":false},{"text":"Theatreland","correct":true},{"text":"Westminster","correct":false},{"text":"Hyde Park","correct":false}],"explanation":"London’s west end, also known as ‘Theatreland’, is particularly well known for its theatres."},
  {"id":"4721","question":"Which two of the following are key roles of school governors?","answers":[{"text":"Monitoring student's behaviour","correct":false},{"text":"Monitoring and evaluating school performance","correct":true},{"text":"Setting the strategic direction of the school","correct":true},{"text":"Giving awards to the best students of the school","correct":false}],"explanation":"Governors and school boards have an important part to play in raising school standards. They have three key roles: setting the strategic direction of the school, ensuring accountability and monitoring and evaluating school performance."},
  {"id":"4722","question":"What led the American colonies to want their independence from Britain?","answers":[{"text":"The British government wanted to control their borders","correct":false},{"text":"They were running out of resources","correct":false},{"text":"The British government wanted to tax them","correct":true},{"text":"There were not enough jobs for the local people","correct":false}],"explanation":"The British government wanted to tax the colonies."},
  {"id":"4723","question":"When did the Black Death","answers":[{"text":"The Golden Age","correct":false},{"text":"The Stone Age","correct":false},{"text":"The Middle Ages","correct":true},{"text":"The Iron Age","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1348 (Middle Ages) the Black Death came to Britain."},
  {"id":"4724","question":"Who was the leader of the suffragettes, the group that campaigned for women’s rights to vote?","answers":[{"text":"Queen Victoria","correct":false},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false},{"text":"Florence Nightingale","correct":false},{"text":"Emmeline Pankhurst","correct":true}],"explanation":"Emmeline Pankhurst was the leader of the suffragettes."},
  {"id":"4725","question":"Cardiff is the capital city of which country?","answers":[{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":true}],"explanation":"The capital city of Wales is Cardiff."},
  {"id":"4726","question":"During the Great Depression in the 1930s which industry was badly affected?","answers":[{"text":"Housing construction","correct":false},{"text":"Shipbuilding","correct":true},{"text":"Automobile","correct":false},{"text":"Aviation","correct":false}],"explanation":"During the ‘Great Depression’ in the 1930s the traditional heavy industries such as shipbuilding were badly affected."},
  {"id":"4727","question":"Who was the first man in the world to run 1 mile in under 4 minutes?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Chris Hoy","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Roger Bannister","correct":true},{"text":"David Weir","correct":false},{"text":"Mo Farah","correct":false}],"explanation":"Sir Roger Bannister was the first man in the world to run a mile in under four minutes, in 1954."},
  {"id":"4728","question":"Which jubilee did Queen Elizabeth II celebrate in 2012?","answers":[{"text":"Golden Jubilee","correct":false},{"text":"Silver Jubilee","correct":false},{"text":"Platinum Jubilee","correct":false},{"text":"Diamond Jubilee","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Queen has reigned since her father’s death in 1952, and in 2012 she celebrated her Diamond Jubilee (60 years as queen)."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-4/
  {"id":"4729","question":"What was the last battle between Great Britain and France?","answers":[{"text":"The Battle of Trafalgar","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Waterloo","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Hastings","correct":false},{"text":"Battle of Agincourt","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1815, the French Wars ended with the defeat of the Emperor Napoleon by the Duke of Wellington at the Battle of Waterloo."},
  {"id":"4730","question":"Which flower is associated with Wales?","answers":[{"text":"Daffodil","correct":true},{"text":"Rose","correct":false},{"text":"Shamrock","correct":false},{"text":"Thistle","correct":false}],"explanation":"The flower associated with Wales is the daffodil."},
  {"id":"4731","question":"During the reign of Charles II parts of London were destroyed, what was the cause of this destruction?","answers":[{"text":"A war","correct":false},{"text":"A flood","correct":false},{"text":"A fire","correct":true},{"text":"An earthquake","correct":false}],"explanation":"During Charles II’s reign, a great fire destroyed much of the city, including many churches and St Paul’s Cathedral."},
  {"id":"4732","question":"How often are general elections held in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Every 3 years","correct":false},{"text":"Every 4 years","correct":false},{"text":"Every 5 years","correct":true},{"text":"Every 10 years","correct":false}],"explanation":"MPs are elected at a General Election, which is held at least every five years."},
  {"id":"4733","question":"Scotland has its own banknotes, which are valid everywhere in the UK.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4734","question":"What charity works to preserve important buildings, coastline and countryside in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Shelter","correct":false},{"text":"Age UK","correct":false},{"text":"Crisis","correct":false},{"text":"The National Trust","correct":true}],"explanation":"The National Trust is a charity that works to preserve important buildings, coastline and countryside in the UK."},
  {"id":"4735","question":"Great Britain refers only to England, Wales and Scotland.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4736","question":"Who was the tribal leader who fought against the Romans?","answers":[{"text":"Cleopatra","correct":false},{"text":"Claudia","correct":false},{"text":"Boudicca","correct":true},{"text":"St Augustine","correct":false}],"explanation":"One of the tribal leaders who fought against the Romans was Boudicca, the queen of the Iceni in what is now eastern England."},
  {"id":"4737","question":"Who was voted the greatest Briton of all time in 2002?","answers":[{"text":"Isaac Newton","correct":false},{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":true},{"text":"Alexander Fleming","correct":false},{"text":"Mo Farat","correct":false}],"explanation":"Winston Churchill remains a much-admired figure to this day, and in 2002 was voted the greatest Briton of all time by the public."},
  {"id":"4738","question":"Which two houses form the UK Parliament?","answers":[{"text":"The House of Lords","correct":true},{"text":"House of Members","correct":false},{"text":"House of Commons","correct":true},{"text":"House of Fraser","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UK Parliament is formed of the House of Commons and the House of Lords."},
  {"id":"4739","question":"When did women get the right to vote at the same age as men?","answers":[{"text":"1918","correct":false},{"text":"1928","correct":true},{"text":"1938","correct":false},{"text":"1948","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1928, women were given the right to vote at the age of 21, the same as men."},
  {"id":"4740","question":"Who is the head of the Church of England? ","answers":[{"text":"The Prime Minister","correct":false},{"text":"The Archbishop of Canterbury","correct":false},{"text":"The Pope","correct":false},{"text":"The monarch","correct":true}],"explanation":"The monarch is the head of the Church of England."},
  {"id":"4741","question":"What sort of event is the Grand National?","answers":[{"text":"Rugby","correct":false},{"text":"Golf","correct":false},{"text":"Horse Racing","correct":true},{"text":"Tennis","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Grand National is a horse racing event."},
  {"id":"4742","question":"What type of literature are the Canterbury Tales?","answers":[{"text":"Poems","correct":true},{"text":"Novels","correct":false},{"text":"Jokes","correct":false},{"text":"Fables","correct":false}],"explanation":"Geoffrey Chaucer wrote a series of poems in English about a group of people going to Canterbury on a pilgrimage. This collection of poems is called The Canterbury Tales."},
  {"id":"4743","question":"When is Christmas Day?","answers":[{"text":"24th of December","correct":false},{"text":"25th of December","correct":true},{"text":"26th of December","correct":false},{"text":"27th of December","correct":false}],"explanation":"Christmas Day is celebrated on the 25th of December."},
  {"id":"4744","question":"Who supported King Charles I during the Civil War?","answers":[{"text":"Roundheads","correct":false},{"text":"Suffragettes","correct":false},{"text":"Quakers","correct":false},{"text":"Cavaliers","correct":true}],"explanation":"During the civil war between the king and Parliament the country split into those who supported the king (the Cavaliers) and those who supported Parliament (the Roundheads)."},
  {"id":"4745","question":"What battle is commemorated in the Bayeux Tapestry?","answers":[{"text":"The Battle of Waterloo","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Trafalgar","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Hastings","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Britain","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Battle of Hastings is commemorated in a great piece of embroidery, known as the Bayeux tapestry."},
  {"id":"4746","question":"Where was Anne Boleyn, the wife of Henry VIII, executed?","answers":[{"text":"Houses of the Parliament","correct":false},{"text":"Stonehenge","correct":false},{"text":"Tower of London","correct":true},{"text":"Whitehall","correct":false}],"explanation":"Anne Boleyn was unpopular in the country and was accused of taking lovers. She was executed at the Tower of London."},
  {"id":"4747","question":"Racial crime and smoking in public places are examples of:","answers":[{"text":"Civil offences","correct":false},{"text":"Criminal offences","correct":true}],"explanation":"Racial crime and smoking in public places are examples of criminal offences."},
  {"id":"4748","question":"What type of character was played by Charlie Chaplin?","answers":[{"text":"A superhero","correct":false},{"text":"A tramp","correct":true},{"text":"A scientific genius","correct":false},{"text":"A bandit","correct":false}],"explanation":"Sir Charles (Charlie) Chaplin became famous in silent movies for his tramp character and was one of many British actors to make a career in Hollywood."},
  {"id":"4749","question":"You have to be at least 21 years old to stand as MP.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"This statement is false. Anyone aged 18 or over can stand for election as an MP but they are unlikely to win unless they have been nominated to represent one of the major political parties. These are the Conservative Party, the Labour Party, the Liberal Democrats, or one of the parties representing Scottish, Welsh or Northern Irish interests."},
  {"id":"4750","question":"Who developed the radar?","answers":[{"text":"John Logie Baird","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Frank Whittle","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Christopher Cockrell","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Robert Watson-Watt","correct":true}],"explanation":"Sir Robert Watson-Watt developed the radar."},
  {"id":"4751","question":"Where is the official home of the Prime Minister?","answers":[{"text":"18 Oxford Street","correct":false},{"text":"Buckingham Palace","correct":false},{"text":"Windsor Castle","correct":false},{"text":"10 Downing Street","correct":true}],"explanation":"The official home of the Prime Minister is 10 Downing Street."},
  {"id":"4752","question":"By law, which TWO types of media have to give a balanced coverage of all political parties and equal time to rival viewpoints before an election?","answers":[{"text":"Television","correct":true},{"text":"Internet","correct":false},{"text":"Newspapers","correct":false},{"text":"Radio","correct":true}],"explanation":"By law, radio and television coverage of the political parties must be balanced and so equal time has to be given to rival viewpoints."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-5/
  {"id":"4755","question":"When does Easter take place?","answers":[{"text":"November or December","correct":false},{"text":"January or February","correct":false},{"text":"March or April","correct":true},{"text":"May or June","correct":false}],"explanation":"Easter takes place in March or April."},
  {"id":"4756","question":"Which of the following is not a valid UK coin?","answers":[{"text":"1p","correct":false},{"text":"5p","correct":false},{"text":"25p","correct":true},{"text":"£1","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are no 25p coins in the UK currency."},
  {"id":"4757","question":"Where is the Eden Project located?","answers":[{"text":"Dorset","correct":false},{"text":"Cornwall","correct":true},{"text":"Devon","correct":false},{"text":"Somerset","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Eden Project is located in Cornwall, in the south west of England."},
  {"id":"4758","question":"St Helena and the Falkland Islands are part of Great Britain.\n\n","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"There are also several British overseas territories in other parts of the world, such as St Helena and the Falkland Islands. They are also linked to the UK but are not part of it."},
  {"id":"4759","question":"Which two of the following are fundamental principles of British life?","answers":[{"text":"Monarchy","correct":false},{"text":"The rule of law","correct":true},{"text":"Democracy","correct":true},{"text":"Join a political party","correct":false}],"explanation":"The fundamental principles of British life include: democracy, the rule of law, individual liberty, tolerance of those with different faiths and beliefs and participation in community life."},
  {"id":"4760","question":"Where should you register if you want to become part of a jury?","answers":[{"text":"The electoral register","correct":true},{"text":"Your local church","correct":false},{"text":"The NHS","correct":false},{"text":"The British Embassy","correct":false}],"explanation":"People on the electoral register are randomly selected to serve on a jury. Therefore, if you want to be selected to form part of a jury you have to be on the electoral register and be between 18 to 70 years old."},
  {"id":"4761","question":"What sort of church is the Church of Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"Catholic","correct":false},{"text":"Baptist","correct":false},{"text":"Presbyterian","correct":true},{"text":"Methodist","correct":false}],"explanation":"In Scotland, the national Church is the Church of Scotland, which is a Presbyterian Church."},
  {"id":"4762","question":"Where does golf come from?","answers":[{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"Australia","correct":false},{"text":"Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":true}],"explanation":"The modern game of golf can be traced back to 15th century Scotland."},
  {"id":"4763","question":"When do the television and newspapers have stories that are jokes until midday?","answers":[{"text":"Valentine’s Day","correct":false},{"text":"Boxing Day","correct":false},{"text":"Halloween","correct":false},{"text":"April Fool’s Day","correct":true}],"explanation":"On April Fool’s Day, the 1st of April the television and newspapers often have stories that are April Fool jokes."},
  {"id":"4764","question":"What king was defeated by Oliver Cromwell during the Civil War and hid in an oak tree before escaping to Europe?","answers":[{"text":"Richard III","correct":false},{"text":"Charles II","correct":true},{"text":"James I","correct":false},{"text":"Henry IV","correct":false}],"explanation":"The correct answer is Charles II."},
  {"id":"4765","question":"Who was the father of Queen Elizabeth I?","answers":[{"text":"Edward I","correct":false},{"text":"Henry V","correct":false},{"text":"Henry VII","correct":false},{"text":"Henry VIII","correct":true}],"explanation":"The father of Queen Elizabeth I was Henry VIII."},
  {"id":"4753","question":"Complaints against the police can only be made by writing to the ","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"Anyone can make a complaint about the police by going to a police station and writing to the Chief Constable of the police force involved. Complaints can also be made to an independent body: the Independent Police Complaints Commission in England and Wales, the Police Complaints Commissioner for Scotland or the Police Ombudsman for Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"4754","question":"Who is the patron Saint of Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"St George","correct":false},{"text":"St Patrick","correct":true},{"text":"St Andrew","correct":false},{"text":"St David","correct":false}],"explanation":"The patron Saint of Northern Ireland is St Patrick."},
  {"id":"4767","question":"What is the name of the period when new ideas about politics, philosophy and science were developed?","answers":[{"text":"The Enlightenment","correct":true},{"text":"The Glorious Revolution","correct":false},{"text":"The Swinging Sixties","correct":false},{"text":"The Reformation","correct":false}],"explanation":"During the 18th century, new ideas about politics, philosophy and science were developed. This is often called ‘the Enlightenment’."},
  {"id":"4768","question":"Which of the following statements is TRUE:","answers":[{"text":"Mary Stuart (‘Mary, Queen of Scots’) was a Protestant","correct":false},{"text":"Mary Stuart (‘Mary, Queen of Scots’) was a Catholic","correct":true}],"explanation":"Mary Stuart (‘Mary, Queen of Scots’) was a Catholic."},
  {"id":"4769","question":"Which of the following is an example of civil law?","answers":[{"text":"To sell tobacco products to anyone under the age of 18","correct":false},{"text":"To buy alcohol for people who are under the age of 18","correct":false},{"text":"Discrimination in the workplace","correct":true},{"text":"To carry a weapon of any kind, even if it is for self-defence","correct":false}],"explanation":"Discrimination in the workplace is an example of civil law."},
  {"id":"4770","question":"In which battle did Admiral Nelson die?","answers":[{"text":"The Battle of Hastings","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Waterloo","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Trafalgar","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Bannockburn","correct":false}],"explanation":"Admiral Nelson was in charge of the British fleet at the Battle of Trafalgar and was killed in the battle."},
  {"id":"4766","question":"William of Orange was asked by Protestants to invade England and proclaim himself king. But, when William reached England, there was no resistance and he took over the throne. This event was later Known as:","answers":[{"text":"The 'Glorious Revolution'","correct":true},{"text":"The Restoration","correct":false},{"text":"The 'Great Depression'","correct":false},{"text":"The 'Blitz'","correct":false}],"explanation":"William of Orange was asked by Protestants to invade England and proclaim himself king. When William reached England, there was no resistance and he took over the throne. This event was later called the ‘Glorious Revolution’."},
  {"id":"4771","question":"What sort of charity is ‘Friends of the Earth’?","answers":[{"text":"An environmental charity","correct":true},{"text":"A medical research charity","correct":false},{"text":"A charity working with pets","correct":false},{"text":"A charity working with older people","correct":false}],"explanation":"Friends of the Earth is an environmental charity."},
  {"id":"4772","question":"If a husband forces his wife to have sex he can be charged with rape.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"4773","question":"In which country of the British Empire did the Boer War (1899-1902) take place?","answers":[{"text":"Netherlands","correct":false},{"text":"Falkland Islands","correct":false},{"text":"Gibraltar","correct":false},{"text":"South Africa","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Boer War of 1899 to 1902 took place in South Africa with settlers from the Netherlands called the Boers."},
  {"id":"4774","question":"Which of the following actions is known as “canvassing”?","answers":[{"text":"Donating blood to help people","correct":false},{"text":"Volunteering for an environmental charity","correct":false},{"text":"Caring for animals at a local rescue shelter","correct":false},{"text":"Persuading people to vote for a political party","correct":true}],"explanation":"Members of political parties persuade people to vote for their candidates – for instance, by handing out leaflets in the street or by knocking on people’s doors and asking for their support. This is called ‘canvassing’."},
  {"id":"4775","question":"Which novel written by JRR Tolkien was voted the country’s best-loved novel in 2003?","answers":[{"text":"Oliver Twist","correct":false},{"text":"James Bond","correct":false},{"text":"Pride and Prejudice","correct":false},{"text":"The Lord of the Rings","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 2003, the Lord of the Rings by JRR Tolkien was voted the country’s best-loved novel."},
  {"id":"4776","question":"When did Germany invade Poland?","answers":[{"text":"1942","correct":false},{"text":"1941","correct":false},{"text":"1940","correct":false},{"text":"1939","correct":true}],"explanation":"Germany invaded Poland in 1939."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-6/
  {"id":"4777","question":"As a British citizen what are your responsibilities (choose two answers)?","answers":[{"text":"To respect and obey the law","correct":true},{"text":"To walk your dog only during the day","correct":false},{"text":"To go to church on Sunday","correct":false},{"text":"To look after yourself and your family","correct":true}],"explanation":"If you wish to be a permanent resident or citizen of the UK, you should: respect and obey the law, look after yourself and your family, respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions, treat others with fairness and look after the area in which you live and the environment."},
  {"id":"4778","question":"Who made the first coins to be minted in Britain?","answers":[{"text":"The people of the Stone Age","correct":false},{"text":"The Anglo-saxons","correct":false},{"text":"The people of the Iron Age","correct":true},{"text":"The Romans","correct":false}],"explanation":"The people of the Iron Age made the first coins to be minted in Britain, some inscribed with the names of Iron Age kings. This marks the beginnings of British history."},
  {"id":"4779","question":"Who built the Tower of London?","answers":[{"text":"William the Conqueror","correct":true},{"text":"Queen Victoria","correct":false},{"text":"Queen Elizabeth I","correct":false},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false}],"explanation":"William the Conqueror."},
  {"id":"4780","question":"There are 15 national parks in England, Wales and Scotland. What are national parks?","answers":[{"text":"Giant greenhouses","correct":false},{"text":"Land formations of columns made from volcanic lava","correct":false},{"text":"Areas of protected countryside","correct":true},{"text":"Medieval buildings","correct":false}],"explanation":"National Parks are areas of protected countryside that everyone can visit, and where people live, work and look after the landscape."},
  {"id":"4781","question":"Northern Ireland has its own established church.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. There is no established Church in Wales or Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"4782","question":"Which three territories form Great Britain?","answers":[{"text":"Wales","correct":true},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"England","correct":true},{"text":"Scotland","correct":true}],"explanation":"‘Great Britain’ refers only to England, Scotland and Wales, not to Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"4783","question":"How often are ‘Prime Minister’s Questions’ held in the parliament? ","answers":[{"text":"Every day","correct":false},{"text":"Every week","correct":true},{"text":"Every two weeks","correct":false},{"text":"Once a month","correct":false}],"explanation":"Prime Minister’s Questions takes place every week while Parliament is sitting."},
  {"id":"4784","question":"Which king was executed in 1649?","answers":[{"text":"James I","correct":false},{"text":"Charles II","correct":false},{"text":"James VII","correct":false},{"text":"Charles I","correct":true}],"explanation":"The correct answer is Charles I."},
  {"id":"4785","question":"Where was William Shakespeare born?","answers":[{"text":"Manchester","correct":false},{"text":"Oldham","correct":false},{"text":"Stratford-upon-Avon","correct":true},{"text":"Lincolnshire","correct":false}],"explanation":"Shakespeare was born in Stratford-upon-Avon, England."},
  {"id":"4786","question":"Which two of the following are famous British Paralympians?","answers":[{"text":"Dame Kelly Holmes","correct":false},{"text":"Baroness Tanni Grey-Thompson","correct":true},{"text":"Jayne Torvill","correct":false},{"text":"Ellie Simmonds","correct":true}],"explanation":"Baroness Tanni Grey-Thompson and Ellie Simmonds are the correct answers."},
  {"id":"4787","question":"Who was reigning in England when English settlers first began to colonise the eastern coast of America?","answers":[{"text":"Queen Victoria","correct":false},{"text":"Henry VIII","correct":false},{"text":"Elizabeth I","correct":true},{"text":"Charles II","correct":false}],"explanation":"In Elizabeth I’s time, English settlers first began to colonise the eastern coast of America."},
  {"id":"4788","question":"Scotland and Wales use a system called ‘individual registration’ where all those entitled to vote must complete their own registration form.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. Northern Ireland uses a system called ‘individual registration’ and all those entitled to vote must complete their own registration form."},
  {"id":"4789","question":"On what day is the birth of Jesus Christ celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"Father’s Day","correct":false},{"text":"Christmas Day","correct":true},{"text":"New Year","correct":false},{"text":"Boxing Day","correct":false}],"explanation":"Christmas Day, 25th of December, celebrates the birth of Jesus Christ."},
  {"id":"4790","question":"What sort of battle was the ‘Battle of Britain’, fought between Germany and Britain in the summer of 1940?","answers":[{"text":"A battle in the sea","correct":false},{"text":"An aerial battle","correct":true},{"text":"A battle in the mountains","correct":false},{"text":"A battle without rifles","correct":false}],"explanation":"‘The Battle of Britain’ was a crucial aerial battle fought between Germany and Britain in the summer of 1940."},
  {"id":"4791","question":"Where is Swansea located?","answers":[{"text":"England","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":true}],"explanation":"Swansea it is located in Wales."},
  {"id":"4799","question":"Which two political parties formed a coalition in 2010?","answers":[{"text":"The Conservative Party","correct":true},{"text":"The Green Party","correct":false},{"text":"The Labour Party","correct":false},{"text":"The Liberal Democrats Party","correct":true}],"explanation":"In May 2010 the Conservative and Liberal Democrat parties formed a coalition and the leader of the Conservative Party, David Cameron, became Prime Minister."},
  {"id":"4792","question":"Who established the Church of England?","answers":[{"text":"Henry VIII","correct":true},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false},{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":false},{"text":"William of Orange","correct":false}],"explanation":"The correct answer is Henry VIII."},
  {"id":"4793","question":"In 1348, one third of the population in England, Wales and Scotland died as a result of which disease?","answers":[{"text":"Measles","correct":false},{"text":"Leprosy","correct":false},{"text":"Smallpox","correct":false},{"text":"The Black Death","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 1348, a disease, probably a form of plague, came to Britain. This was known as the Black Death. One third of the population of England died and a similar proportion in Scotland and Wales."},
  {"id":"4795","question":"Haggis is a traditional food from which area?","answers":[{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"England","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":true}],"explanation":"Haggis is a traditional food from Scotland."},
  {"id":"4797","question":"Which court deals with minor criminal offences in Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"The Sheriff Court","correct":false},{"text":"The Magistrates' Court","correct":false},{"text":"The Crown Court","correct":false},{"text":"The Justice of the Peace Court","correct":true}],"explanation":"In Scotland, minor criminal offences go to a Justice of the Peace Court."},
  {"id":"4798","question":"Which two of the following records give us information about England during the reign of William I?","answers":[{"text":"The Magna Carta","correct":false},{"text":"The Domesday Book","correct":true},{"text":"The Bayeux Tapestry","correct":true},{"text":"The Canterbury Tales","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Domesday Book and the Bayeux Tapestry."},
  {"id":"4794","question":"In 1913, the British government promised ‘Home Rule’ for Ireland, why were changes in Ireland delayed until 1921?","answers":[{"text":"Due to the outbreak of the First World War","correct":true},{"text":"Due to the outbreak of the Second World War","correct":false},{"text":"Because there was not a king on the British throne","correct":false},{"text":"Due to the outbreak of the Black Death","correct":false}],"explanation":"The outbreak of the First World War led the British government to postpone any changes in Ireland."},
  {"id":"4796","question":"Which of the following statements is true:","answers":[{"text":"Elizabeth I was a Protestant and she succeeded in finding a balance between the views of the Catholics and the more extreme Protestants.","correct":true},{"text":"Elizabeth I was a Catholic and she succeeded in finding a balance between the views of the Catholics and the more extreme Protestants.","correct":false}],"explanation":"Elizabeth I was a Protestant and she succeeded in finding a balance between the views of the Catholics and the more extreme Protestants."},
  {"id":"4800","question":"Which two documents do you need to apply for a National Insurance number?","answers":[{"text":"A document with your address on it, such as a tenancy agreement","correct":false},{"text":"Documents that prove that you have permission to work in the UK","correct":true},{"text":"A contract from your employer","correct":false},{"text":"Documents that prove your identity","correct":true}],"explanation":"To apply for a National Insurance number you need documents that prove your identity and that you have permission to work in the UK."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-7/
  {"id":"5060","question":"As a British citizen, you should:","answers":[{"text":"Respect and obey the law","correct":true},{"text":"Vote in all elections","correct":false},{"text":"Take part in religious activities","correct":false},{"text":"Look after the area in which you live and the environment","correct":true}],"explanation":"As a British citizen you should respect and obey the law and look after the area in which you live and the environment are the correct answers."},
  {"id":"5061","question":"When is Halloween celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"5th of November","correct":false},{"text":"11th of November","correct":false},{"text":"31st of October","correct":true},{"text":"1st of April","correct":false}],"explanation":"Halloween is celebrated on the 31st of October."},
  {"id":"5063","question":"The Bill of Rights in 1689 gave women the right to vote.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. The Bill of Rights, 1689, confirmed the rights of Parliament and the limits of the king’s power."},
  {"id":"5068","question":"What is the name of the most famous cricket competition played between England and Australia?","answers":[{"text":"The Ashes","correct":true},{"text":"The Six Nations Championship","correct":false},{"text":"The Grand National","correct":false},{"text":"The Australian Open","correct":false}],"explanation":"The most famous cricket competition is the Ashes, which is a series of Test matches played between England and Australia."},
  {"id":"5066","question":"What was the biggest source of employment during the 18th century?","answers":[{"text":"Fishing","correct":false},{"text":"Teaching","correct":false},{"text":"Aircraft industry","correct":false},{"text":"Manufacturing","correct":true}],"explanation":"During the 18th century, manufacturing jobs became the main source of employment in Britain."},
  {"id":"5065","question":"In 1314 the Scottish, led by Robert the Bruce, defeated the English at the battle of Bannockburn, and Scotland remained unconquered by the English.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5064","question":"Which of the following is an example of criminal offence?","answers":[{"text":"Smoking in public places where it is not allowed","correct":true},{"text":"Disputes about faulty goods or services","correct":false},{"text":"Disputes about an unfair dismissal in the workplace","correct":false},{"text":"A dispute between the landlord and the tenants who have not paid the rent","correct":false}],"explanation":"Smoking in public places. It is against the law to smoke tobacco products in nearly every enclosed public place in the UK. There are signs displayed to tell you where you cannot smoke."},
  {"id":"5067","question":"Which Scottish clan was killed for not taking the oath?","answers":[{"text":"The MacLaine of Lochbuie","correct":false},{"text":"The McDowalls of Garthland","correct":false},{"text":"The Macpherson of Cluny","correct":false},{"text":"The MacDonalds of Glencoe","correct":true}],"explanation":"The MacDonalds of Glencoe."},
  {"id":"5069","question":"Which two issues can the devolved administrations pass laws on?","answers":[{"text":"Defence","correct":false},{"text":"Social security","correct":false},{"text":"Health","correct":true},{"text":"Education","correct":true}],"explanation":"Policy and laws governing defence, foreign affairs, immigration, taxation and social security all remain under central UK government control. However, many other public services, such as health and education, are controlled by the devolved administrations."},
  {"id":"5070","question":"The assassination of the Archduke Franz Ferdinand of Austria in 1914 led to which of the following wars?","answers":[{"text":"The Crimean War","correct":false},{"text":"The First World War","correct":true},{"text":"The Civil War","correct":false},{"text":"The Second World War","correct":false}],"explanation":"On 28 June 1914, Archduke Franz Ferdinand of Austria was assassinated. This set off a chain of events leading to the First World War (1914-18)."},
  {"id":"5062","question":"What is the capital city of Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"Glasgow","correct":false},{"text":"St Andrews","correct":false},{"text":"Edinburgh","correct":true},{"text":"Aberdeen","correct":false}],"explanation":"The capital city of Scotland is Edinburgh."},
  {"id":"5071","question":"In 1833 the Emancipation Act abolished slavery throughout the British Empire.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5072","question":"What is the name of the process by which many Scottish landlords destroyed individual small farms (known as ‘crofts’) to make space for large flocks of sheep and cattle?","answers":[{"text":"The Black Death","correct":false},{"text":"The Corn Removal","correct":false},{"text":"The Highland Clearances","correct":true},{"text":"The Enlightenment","correct":false}],"explanation":"A process began which became known as the ‘Highland Clearances’. Many Scottish landlords destroyed individual small farms (known as ‘crofts’) to make space for large flocks of sheep and cattle."},
  {"id":"5059","question":"The Falkland Islands are a British overseas territory and are part of the United Kingdom.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Falkland Islands are a British overseas territory. They are also linked to the UK but are not part of it."},
  {"id":"5074","question":"Which two of the following are Civil War Battles?","answers":[{"text":"The Battle of Waterloo","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Marston Moor","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Naseby","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Agincourt","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Battles of Marston Moor and Naseby."},
  {"id":"5075","question":"What was the name of the activist group who fought for the women’s right to vote?","answers":[{"text":"Chartists","correct":false},{"text":"Beefeaters","correct":false},{"text":"Suffragettes","correct":true},{"text":"Quakers","correct":false}],"explanation":"In the late 19th and early 20th centuries, an increasing number of women campaigned and demonstrated for greater rights and, in particular, the right to vote. They formed the women’s suffrage movement and became known as the ‘suffragettes’."},
  {"id":"5076","question":"What UK landmark was voted as Britain’s favourite view in 2007?","answers":[{"text":"The Big Ben","correct":false},{"text":"Lake District","correct":true},{"text":"Snowdonia","correct":false},{"text":"The London Eye","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 2007, television viewers voted Wastwater (Lake District) as Britain’s favourite view."},
  {"id":"5077","question":"Who were the first people to live in Britain in what we call the Stone Age?","answers":[{"text":"Farmers","correct":false},{"text":"Peasants","correct":false},{"text":"Hunter-gatherers","correct":true},{"text":"Pirates","correct":false}],"explanation":"The first people to live in Britain were hunter-gatherers."},
  {"id":"5073","question":"What is the name of the movement against the authority of the Pope and the ideas of the Catholic Church that took place during the reign of Henry VIII?","answers":[{"text":"The Reformation","correct":true},{"text":"The Enlightenment","correct":false},{"text":"The Glorious Revolution","correct":false},{"text":"The Renaissance","correct":false}],"explanation":"The correct answer is the Reformation."},
  {"id":"5078","question":"What do you need to do to apply for a National Insurance Number?","answers":[{"text":"Contact the NHS","correct":false},{"text":"Contact the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP)","correct":true},{"text":"Contact your local MP","correct":false},{"text":"Ask you employer to get it for you","correct":false}],"explanation":"If you have permission to work in the UK, you will need to telephone the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) to arrange to get a National Insurance number."},
  {"id":"5079","question":"Which of the following is a major horse-racing event in England?","answers":[{"text":"The Wimbledon Championship","correct":false},{"text":"Royal Ascot","correct":true},{"text":"The Open Championship","correct":false},{"text":"The Six Nations Championship","correct":false}],"explanation":"Famous horse-racing events include: Royal Ascot , a five-day race meeting in Berkshire attended by members of the Royal Family; the Grand National at Aintree near Liverpool; and the Scottish Grand National at Ayr."},
  {"id":"5080","question":"How many members form a jury in Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"12","correct":false},{"text":"14","correct":false},{"text":"15","correct":true},{"text":"20","correct":false}],"explanation":"In Scotland a jury has 15 members."},
  {"id":"5081","question":"What is known as Lent?","answers":[{"text":"The 40 days before Christmas","correct":false},{"text":"The 40 days after Easter","correct":false},{"text":"The 40 days before Easter","correct":true},{"text":"The 40 days after Christmas","correct":false}],"explanation":"The 40 days before Easter are known as Lent."},
  {"id":"5082","question":"When was the last successful foreign invasion of England?","answers":[{"text":"1415","correct":false},{"text":"1314","correct":false},{"text":"1066","correct":true},{"text":"1200","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Norman Conquest was the last successful foreign invasion of England in 1066."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-8/
  {"id":"5251","question":"World War II started as a result of Germany invading which country?","answers":[{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Russia","correct":false},{"text":"Poland","correct":true},{"text":"Austria","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Second World War started when Hitler invaded Poland in 1939. Britain and France declared war in order to stop his aggression."},
  {"id":"5252","question":"Which flower is associated with Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"The Shamrock","correct":false},{"text":"The Rose","correct":false},{"text":"The Daffodil","correct":false},{"text":"The Thistle","correct":true}],"explanation":"The flower associated with Scotland is the thistle."},
  {"id":"5253","question":"Police complaints can only be made by writing to the Chief Constable of the police force involved.\n\n","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"Anyone can make a complaint about the police by going to a police station and writing to the Chief Constable of the police force involved. Complaints can also be made to an independent body: the Independent Police Complaints Commission in England and Wales, the Police Complaints Commissioner for Scotland or the Police Ombudsman for Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"5254","question":"Which of the following is a responsibility of the Home Secretary?","answers":[{"text":"Economy","correct":false},{"text":"Crime","correct":true},{"text":"Education","correct":false},{"text":"Defence","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Home Secretary is responsible for crime, policing and immigration."},
  {"id":"5443","question":"When is St David’s day celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"1st March","correct":true},{"text":"17th March","correct":false},{"text":"23rd April","correct":false},{"text":"17th April","correct":false}],"explanation":"St David’s day, patron of Wales, is celebrated on the 1st of March."},
  {"id":"5444","question":"What happened to ‘Mary, Queen of Scots’ after she spent 20 years in prison?","answers":[{"text":"She became Queen of England","correct":false},{"text":"She was sent to France","correct":false},{"text":"She escaped to Denmark","correct":false},{"text":"She was executed","correct":true}],"explanation":"Mary was eventually executed, accused of plotting against Elizabeth I."},
  {"id":"5445","question":"Which of the following lines are from the National Anthem (choose two options)?","answers":[{"text":"We shall never surrender","correct":false},{"text":"God save our gracious Queen!","correct":true},{"text":"Send her victorious","correct":true},{"text":"The darling buds of May","correct":false}],"explanation":"The first verse of the National Anthem is: ‘God save our gracious Queen! Long live our noble Queen! God save the Queen! Send her victorious, Happy and glorious, Long to reign over us, God save the Queen!’"},
  {"id":"5258","question":"Northern Ireland and Scotland have their own banknotes, which are valid everywhere in the UK.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5446","question":"How many national parks are there in England, Wales and Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"25","correct":false},{"text":"15","correct":true},{"text":"18","correct":false},{"text":"42","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are 15 national parks in England, Wales and Scotland."},
  {"id":"5260","question":"Is Northern Ireland part of Great Britain?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}],"explanation":"‘Great Britain’ refers only to England, Scotland and Wales, not to Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"5447","question":"If you are a dog owner, which two things should your dog’s collar have when you go out for a walk?","answers":[{"text":"The owner's address","correct":true},{"text":"The owner's name","correct":true},{"text":"The dog's breed","correct":false},{"text":"The dog's name","correct":false}],"explanation":"All dogs in public places must wear a collar showing the name and address of the owner."},
  {"id":"5448","question":"What day relates to the death of Jesus Christ?","answers":[{"text":"Good Friday","correct":true},{"text":"Easter Sunday","correct":false},{"text":"Easter Monday","correct":false},{"text":"Ash Wednesday","correct":false}],"explanation":"Easter takes place in March or April. It marks the death of Jesus Christ on Good Friday and his rising from the dead on Easter Sunday."},
  {"id":"5449","question":"Who is the heir to the throne of Britain?","answers":[{"text":"The Prince of Wales","correct":true},{"text":"The Prince of Cambridge","correct":false},{"text":"The Prince of Edinburgh","correct":false},{"text":"The Duke of York","correct":false}],"explanation":"Prince Charles (the Prince of Wales), is the heir to the throne."},
  {"id":"5450","question":"What was achieved with the Carta Magna?","answers":[{"text":"It restricted the King's power","correct":true},{"text":"It increased the King's power","correct":false},{"text":"It restricted the rights of the farmers","correct":false},{"text":"It increased women's power","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Magna Carta established the idea that even the king was subject to the law. It protected the rights of the nobility and restricted the king’s power to collect taxes or to make and change laws. In future, the king would need to involve his noblemen in decisions."},
  {"id":"5265","question":"Female genital mutilation (FGM) or taking a girl or woman abroad for FGM is illegal in the UK and it is a criminal offence.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5451","question":"What year were women given the right to vote?","answers":[{"text":"1918","correct":true},{"text":"1925","correct":false},{"text":"1949","correct":false},{"text":"1914","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1918, women over the age of 30 were given voting rights and the right to stand for Parliament, partly in recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the First World War."},
  {"id":"5452","question":"Which two of the following are British overseas territories?","answers":[{"text":"St Helena","correct":true},{"text":"Solomon Islands","correct":false},{"text":"Mauritius","correct":false},{"text":"The Falkland Islands","correct":true}],"explanation":"There are several British overseas territories, such as St Helena and the Falkland Islands. They are linked to the UK but are not part of it."},
  {"id":"5453","question":"Who did the English defeat in 1588?","answers":[{"text":"The Normands","correct":false},{"text":"The Romans","correct":false},{"text":"The Spanish Armada","correct":true},{"text":"The Saxons","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1588 the English defeated the Spanish Armada (a large fleet of ships)."},
  {"id":"5454","question":"Who designed the Cenotaph?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Norman Foster","correct":false},{"text":"Lancelot ‘Capability’ Brown","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Edwin Lutyens","correct":true},{"text":"Isambard Kingdom Brunel","correct":false}],"explanation":"Sir Edwin Lutyens was responsible for designing many war memorials throughout the world, including the Cenotaph in Whitehall."},
  {"id":"5455","question":"How often are the members of the Welsh government elected?","answers":[{"text":"Every 5 years","correct":false},{"text":"Every 2 years","correct":false},{"text":"Every 4 years","correct":true},{"text":"Every 3 years","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are 60 members of the Welsh government or members of the Senedd (MSs) and elections are held every four years using a form of proportional representation."},
  {"id":"5456","question":"During which period did the Beatles become popular and social laws were liberalised?","answers":[{"text":"1960s","correct":true},{"text":"1970s","correct":false},{"text":"1980s","correct":false},{"text":"1950s","correct":false}],"explanation":"The decade of the 1960s was a period of significant social change. It was known as the ‘swinging sixties’. There was growth in British fashion, cinema and popular music. Two well-known pop music groups at the time were The Beatles and The Rolling Stones. It was also a time when social laws were liberalised, for example in relation to divorce and to abortion in England, Wales and Scotland. The position of women in the workplace also improved."},
  {"id":"5457","question":"The Man Booker Prize is awarded in which of the following categories?","answers":[{"text":"Films","correct":false},{"text":"Sport","correct":false},{"text":"Literature","correct":true},{"text":"Music","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Man Booker Prize for Fiction is awarded annually for the best fiction novel (literature) written by an author from the Commonwealth, Ireland or Zimbabwe. It has been awarded since 1968. Past winners include Ian McEwan, Hilary Mantel and Julian Barnes."},
  {"id":"5458","question":"What sort of election takes place when a member of the Parliament (MP) dies or resigns?","answers":[{"text":"Coalition","correct":false},{"text":"Pre-selection","correct":false},{"text":"Random selection","correct":false},{"text":"By-election","correct":true}],"explanation":"If an MP dies or resigns, there will be a fresh election, called a by-election, in his or her constituency."},
  {"id":"5459","question":"What is the Turner Prize? ","answers":[{"text":"A literature award","correct":false},{"text":"A music award","correct":false},{"text":"A contemporary art award","correct":true},{"text":"A theatre award","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Turner Prize was established in 1984 and celebrates contemporary art. The Turner Prize is recognised as one of the most prestigious visual art awards in Europe."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-9/
  {"id":"5514","question":"Which flower is associated with Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"The daffodil","correct":false},{"text":"The thistle","correct":false},{"text":"The shamrock","correct":true},{"text":"The rose","correct":false}],"explanation":"The flower associated with Northern Ireland is the shamrock."},
  {"id":"5491","question":"The last battle between Britain and France was the battle of Waterloo.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5492","question":"£100 is the highest value note in circulation in the UK.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"This statement is false."},
  {"id":"5493","question":"Where is the Lake District National Park located?","answers":[{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"England","correct":true},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false}],"explanation":"Lake District is in England."},
  {"id":"5494","question":"Which two responsibilities will you have as a British citizen?","answers":[{"text":"To buy food locally","correct":false},{"text":"To volunteer in a community project at least once a year","correct":false},{"text":"To look after yourself and your family","correct":true},{"text":"To respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions","correct":true}],"explanation":"If you wish to be a permanent resident or citizen of the UK, you should: respect and obey the law, look after yourself and your family, respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions, treat others with fairness and look after the area in which you live and the environment."},
  {"id":"5495","question":"Who was born in Stratford-upon-Avon? ","answers":[{"text":"Jane Austen","correct":false},{"text":"Charles Dickens","correct":false},{"text":"William Shakespeare","correct":true},{"text":"Thomas Hardy","correct":false}],"explanation":"William Shakespeare was born in Stratford-upon-Avon, England."},
  {"id":"5496","question":"Why is 1928 an important year in women’s voting history?","answers":[{"text":"Women were given the right to vote at the age of 18, the same as men.","correct":false},{"text":"Women were given the right to vote at the age of 25.","correct":false},{"text":"Women were given the right to vote at the age of 30.","correct":false},{"text":"Women were given the right to vote at the age of 21, the same as men.","correct":true}],"explanation":"Women were given the right to vote at the age of 21, the same as men."},
  {"id":"5497","question":"What does Hogmanay refer to?","answers":[{"text":"Christmas Day in Wales","correct":false},{"text":"New Year's Eve in Scotland","correct":true},{"text":"Christmas Day in Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"New Year's Eve in Wales","correct":false}],"explanation":"In Scotland, the 31st of December (New Year’s Eve) is called Hogmanay."},
  {"id":"5498","question":"What is the capital city of Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"Cork","correct":false},{"text":"Edinburgh","correct":false},{"text":"Belfast","correct":true},{"text":"Dublin","correct":false}],"explanation":"The capital city of Northern Ireland is Belfast."},
  {"id":"5499","question":"Which of the following wars took place between 1899 and 1902 in South Africa?","answers":[{"text":"The Hundred Years War","correct":false},{"text":"The Boer War","correct":true},{"text":"The First World War","correct":false},{"text":"The Crimean War","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Boer War."},
  {"id":"5500","question":"Northern Ireland uses a system called ‘individual registration’ and all those entitled to vote must complete their own registration form.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is True."},
  {"id":"5501","question":"Which two of the following policies are not controlled by the devolved administrations?","answers":[{"text":"Health","correct":false},{"text":"Education","correct":false},{"text":"Defence","correct":true},{"text":"Immigration","correct":true}],"explanation":"Policy and laws governing defence, foreign affairs, immigration, taxation and social security all remain under central UK government control. However, many other public services, such as education, are controlled by the devolved administrations."},
  {"id":"5502","question":"How old do citizens of the UK, the Irish Republic or the Commonwealth have to be to stand for public office?","answers":[{"text":"18","correct":true},{"text":"21","correct":false},{"text":"16","correct":false},{"text":"25","correct":false}],"explanation":"Most citizens of the UK, the Irish republic or the Commonwealth aged 18 or over can stand for public office. There are some exceptions, including: members of the armed forces, civil servants and people found guilty of certain criminal offences."},
  {"id":"5515","question":"How did the Government promote policies of free trade during the Victorian Age?","answers":[{"text":"Abolishing a number of taxes on imported goods","correct":true},{"text":"Abolishing the exportation of local produce","correct":false},{"text":"Preventing the importation of cheap raw materials","correct":false},{"text":"Preventing the importation of cheap grain","correct":false}],"explanation":"During Victorian times, the government began to promote policies of free trade, abolishing a number of taxes on imported goods. One example of this was the repealing of the Corn Laws in 1846. These had prevented the import of cheap grain. The reforms helped the development of the British industry, because raw materials could now be imported cheaply."},
  {"id":"5516","question":"Who was Admiral Nelson?","answers":[{"text":"One of the tribal leaders who fought against the Romans","correct":false},{"text":"A British officer in charge of the British army at the Battle of Waterloo","correct":false},{"text":"A British general who established the authority of the English Parliament","correct":false},{"text":"A British officer in charge of the British fleet at the Battle of Trafalgar against the Spanish fleet","correct":true}],"explanation":"Admiral Nelson was in charge of the British fleet at the Battle of Trafalgar against the Spanish fleet and was killed in the battle."},
  {"id":"5517","question":"During the Middle Ages, who were the serfs?","answers":[{"text":"Peasants who had a small area of their lord’s agricultural land","correct":true},{"text":"Soldiers who fought at the Battle of Trafalgar","correct":false},{"text":"Noblemen who formed part of the king’s council of advisers","correct":false},{"text":"A group of skilled people from Holland who came to England during the Middle Ages","correct":false}],"explanation":"Serfs were peasants who had a small area of their lord’s land where they could grow food."},
  {"id":"5518","question":"Which invention lead to the rapid development of the industry in Britain during the 18th and 19th centuries?","answers":[{"text":"The Radar","correct":false},{"text":"The Steam Power","correct":true},{"text":"The Jet Engine","correct":false},{"text":"The Turing Machine","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Industrial Revolution was the rapid development of industry in Britain in the 18th and 19th centuries. Britain was the first country to industrialise on a large scale. It happened because of the development of machinery and the use of steam power."},
  {"id":"5507","question":"MPs can only be contacted by post.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"You can contact MPs by letter or telephone at their constituency office, or at their office in the House of Commons. In addition, many MPs, Assembly members, MSPs and MEPs hold regular local ‘surgeries’, where constituents can go in person to talk about issues that are of concern to them."},
  {"id":"5519","question":"What movement challenged the authority of the Pope?","answers":[{"text":"The Swinging Sixties","correct":false},{"text":"The Reformation","correct":true},{"text":"The Suffragettes","correct":false},{"text":"The Enlightenment","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Reformation was a movement against the authority of the Pope and the ideas and practices of the Roman Catholic Church."},
  {"id":"5520","question":"What English King introduced the Domesday Book?","answers":[{"text":"King Henry V","correct":false},{"text":"King Henry IV","correct":false},{"text":"William the Conqueror","correct":true},{"text":"Harold, the Saxon king of England","correct":false}],"explanation":"William the Conqueror sent people all over England to draw up lists of all the towns and villages. The people who lived there, who owned the land and what animals they owned were also listed. This was called the Domesday Book."},
  {"id":"5521","question":"What did ‘the Butler Act’  introduce in 1944?","answers":[{"text":"Free primary education in England, Wales and Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Free university fees in England, Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Free primary and secondary education in England, Wales and Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Free secondary education in England and Wales","correct":true}],"explanation":"Richard Austen Butler became a Conservative MP in 1923 and held several positions before becoming responsible for education in 1941. In this role, he oversaw the introduction of the Education Act 1944 (often called ‘The Butler Act’), which introduced free secondary education in England and Wales."},
  {"id":"5511","question":"What is the small claims procedure?","answers":[{"text":"An informal way of helping people to settle minor disputes without spending a lot of time and money using a lawyer","correct":true},{"text":"A procedure that helps people to make small home insurance claims in certain circumstances","correct":false}],"explanation":"The small claims procedure is an informal way of helping people to settle minor disputes without spending a lot of time and money using a lawyer."},
  {"id":"5522","question":"What building was constructed in Hyde Park to hold the Great Exhibition of 1851?","answers":[{"text":"The Crystal Palace","correct":true},{"text":"Buckingham Palace","correct":false},{"text":"Kensington Palace","correct":false},{"text":"Apsley House","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1851, the Great Exhibition opened in Hyde Park in the Crystal Palace, a huge building made of steel and glass. Exhibits ranged from huge machines to handmade goods."},
  {"id":"5523","question":"Who was Florence Nightingale?","answers":[{"text":"An economist","correct":false},{"text":"A painter","correct":false},{"text":"A nurse","correct":true},{"text":"A poet","correct":false}],"explanation":"Florence Nightingale was a nurse. She is often regarded as the founder of modern nursing."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-naturalization-test-10/
  {"id":"5524","question":"Who is the patron Saint of England?","answers":[{"text":"St George","correct":true},{"text":"St Patrick","correct":false},{"text":"St David","correct":false},{"text":"St Andrew","correct":false}],"explanation":"The patron Saint of England is St George."},
  {"id":"5525","question":"Where is Loch Lomond and the Trossachs National Park located?","answers":[{"text":"England","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":true},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false}],"explanation":"Loch Lomond and the Trossachs National Park is located in the west of Scotland."},
  {"id":"5526","question":"Wales has its own established church.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. There is no established Church in Wales or Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"5527","question":"What stories are associated with Geoffrey Chaucer?","answers":[{"text":"The Cambridge Tales","correct":false},{"text":"The Eastbourne Tales","correct":false},{"text":"The Canterbury Tales","correct":true},{"text":"The London Tales","correct":false}],"explanation":"Geoffrey Chaucer wrote a series of poems in English about a group of people going to Canterbury on a pilgrimage.  This collection of poems is called The Canterbury Tales"},
  {"id":"5528","question":"When is Boxing Day celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"31st October","correct":false},{"text":"26th December","correct":true},{"text":"24th December","correct":false},{"text":"01st January","correct":false}],"explanation":"Boxing Day is the day after Christmas Day (26th December) and is a public holiday."},
  {"id":"5529","question":"What is the name of the holiday when banks and many other businesses are closed for the day?","answers":[{"text":"Credit Holidays","correct":false},{"text":"Branch Holidays","correct":false},{"text":"Bank Holidays","correct":true},{"text":"Business Holidays","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are public holidays each year called bank holidays, when banks and many other businesses are closed for the day."},
  {"id":"5530","question":"Why were women given the right to vote?","answers":[{"text":"In recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the First World War","correct":true},{"text":"In recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the Second World War","correct":false},{"text":"In recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the Crimean War","correct":false},{"text":"In recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the Civil War","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1918, women over the age of 30 were given voting rights and the right to stand for Parliament, partly in recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the First World War."},
  {"id":"5531","question":"What do you need to drive in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"An ‘L’ plate","correct":false},{"text":"A National Insurance Number","correct":false},{"text":"A valid driving licence","correct":true},{"text":"An ‘R’ plate","correct":false}],"explanation":"In the UK, you must have a driving licence to drive on public roads."},
  {"id":"5532","question":"Where does “the Fringe” festival take place?","answers":[{"text":"Fraserburgh","correct":false},{"text":"Edinburgh","correct":true},{"text":"Inverness","correct":false},{"text":"St Andrews","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Edinburgh Festival takes place in Edinburgh, Scotland, every summer. It is a series of different arts and cultural festivals, with the biggest and most well-known being the Edinburgh Festival Fringe (‘the Fringe’)."},
  {"id":"5533","question":"How many members does the Welsh government have?","answers":[{"text":"150","correct":false},{"text":"120","correct":false},{"text":"90","correct":false},{"text":"60","correct":true}],"explanation":"There are 60 members of the Welsh government or members of the Senedd (MSs) and elections are held every four years using a form of proportional representation."},
  {"id":"5534","question":"The names or photographs of  young people found guilty of a crime can be published in newspapers or used by the media.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. Members of the public are not allowed in Youth Courts, and the name or photographs of the accused young person cannot be published in newspapers or used by the media."},
  {"id":"5535","question":"What was Edward Elgar famous for?","answers":[{"text":"He was a musician","correct":true},{"text":"He was a tennis player","correct":false},{"text":"He was a comedian","correct":false},{"text":"He was an actor","correct":false}],"explanation":"Sir Edward Elgar (1857-1934) was a musician. His best known work is probably the Pomp and Circumstance Marches. March No1 (Land of Hope and Glory) is usually played at the Last Night of the Proms at the Royal Albert Hall."},
  {"id":"5536","question":"Which of the following is not a British banknote?","answers":[{"text":"£50","correct":false},{"text":"£25","correct":true},{"text":"£20","correct":false},{"text":"£5","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are no £25 notes in the UK."},
  {"id":"5548","question":"Where does the Scottish Grand National take place?","answers":[{"text":"Fife","correct":false},{"text":"Edinburgh","correct":false},{"text":"Ayr","correct":true},{"text":"St Andrews","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Scottish Grand National takes place at Ayr."},
  {"id":"5549","question":"When did the UK join the EU?","answers":[{"text":"In 1957","correct":false},{"text":"In 1973","correct":true},{"text":"In 1975","correct":false},{"text":"In 1964","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UK originally decided not to join this group but it became a member in 1973."},
  {"id":"5550","question":"During the reign of Elizabeth I, a large fleet of ships was sent to England to conquer the country and to restore Catholicism, where did this fleet come from?","answers":[{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Portugal","correct":false},{"text":"Spain","correct":true},{"text":"Italy","correct":false}],"explanation":"Elizabeth I became one of the most popular monarchs in English history, particularly after 1588, when the English defeated the Spanish Armada (a large fleet of ships), which had been sent by Spain to conquer England and restore Catholicism."},
  {"id":"5551","question":"What did the Habeas Corpus Act introduce?","answers":[{"text":"That every prisoner has a right to a court hearing","correct":true},{"text":"A salary for members of Parliament (MPs)","correct":false},{"text":"Financial help for the unemployed, old-age pensions and free school meals","correct":false},{"text":"Measures to improve the conditions of workers","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Habeas Corpus Act became law in 1679. This was a very important piece of legislation which remains relevant today. Habeas corpus is Latin for ‘you must present the person in court’. The Act guaranteed that no one could be held prisoner unlawfully. Every prisoner has a right to a court hearing."},
  {"id":"5552","question":"What did Emmeline Pankhurst fight for?","answers":[{"text":"The right to liberty and security","correct":false},{"text":"The right for women to vote","correct":true},{"text":"Freedom of expression","correct":false},{"text":"The right to a fair trial","correct":false}],"explanation":"Emmeline Pankhurst she set up the women’s Franchise League in 1889, which fought to get the vote in local elections for married women. In 1903 she helped found the Women’s Social and Political Union (WSPU). This was the first group whose members were called ‘suffragettes’. The group used civil disobedience as part of their protest to gain the vote for women. In 1918, women over the age of 30 were given voting rights and the right to stand for Parliament, partly in recognition of the contribution women made to the war effort during the First World War."},
  {"id":"5560","question":"What is “the Proms”?","answers":[{"text":"An annual event that gives awards in a range of categories, such as best British group and best British solo artist","correct":false},{"text":"An annual cultural festival which includes music, dance, art and original performances largely in Welsh","correct":false},{"text":"An eight-week summer season of daily orchestral classical music concerts","correct":true},{"text":"Light-hearted plays with music and comedy","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Proms is an eight-week summer season of orchestral classical music that takes place in various venues, including the Royal Albert Hall in London."},
  {"id":"5554","question":"What was Isaac Newton known for?","answers":[{"text":"The discovery of insulin","correct":false},{"text":"The discovery of gravity","correct":true},{"text":"The discovery of penicillin","correct":false},{"text":"The discovery of steam power","correct":false}],"explanation":"Newton’s most famous published work was Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica (‘Mathematical Principle of Natural Philosophy’), which showed how gravity applied to the whole universe."},
  {"id":"5556","question":"When did the WWI come to an end?","answers":[{"text":"In 1922","correct":false},{"text":"In 1918","correct":true},{"text":"In 1945","correct":false},{"text":"In 1943","correct":false}],"explanation":"The World War I ended in 1918."},
  {"id":"5559","question":"Who built a wall in the north of England to keep out the Picts (ancestors of the Scottish people)?","answers":[{"text":"Boudicca","correct":false},{"text":"Emperor Hadrian","correct":true},{"text":"Emperor Claudius","correct":false},{"text":"Julius Caesar","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Emperor Hadrian built a wall in the north of England to keep out the Picts (ancestors of the Scottish people)."},
  {"id":"5555","question":"Which two universities participate in an annual rowing race that takes place on the River Thames?","answers":[{"text":"The University of Oxford","correct":true},{"text":"The University of Cambridge","correct":true},{"text":"The University of Manchester","correct":false},{"text":"The University of Warwick","correct":false}],"explanation":"Rowing is also popular, both as a leisure activity and as a competitive sport. There is a popular yearly race on the Thames between Oxford and Cambridge Universities."},
  {"id":"5547","question":"Does Britain have a written constitution?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}],"explanation":"The British constitution is not written down in any single document, and therefore it is described as ‘unwritten’."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/audio-british-citizenship-test-11/
  {"id":"5359","question":"Is St Helena part of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}],"explanation":"British overseas territories, such as St Helena and the Falkland Islands are linked to the UK but are not part of it."},
  {"id":"5360","question":"Where is Theatreland?","answers":[{"text":"Docklands","correct":false},{"text":"London’s east end","correct":false},{"text":"London’s west end","correct":true},{"text":"London’s south end","correct":false}],"explanation":""},
  {"id":"5361","question":"What is the name of the UK currency?","answers":[{"text":"Euro","correct":false},{"text":"Pound Sterling","correct":true},{"text":"Peso","correct":false},{"text":"Dollar","correct":false}],"explanation":"The currency in the UK is the pound sterling (symbol £)."},
  {"id":"5362","question":"What other name is given to Diwali?","answers":[{"text":"The Festival of Lights","correct":true},{"text":"Ash Wednesday","correct":false},{"text":"Good Friday","correct":false},{"text":"Easter Monday","correct":false}],"explanation":"Diwali is often called the Festival of Lights."},
  {"id":"5363","question":"What is the Enlightenment?","answers":[{"text":"A period of total peace in England","correct":false},{"text":"A period when new ideas about politics, philosophy and science were developed","correct":true},{"text":"A period when England became the largest empire the world had ever seen","correct":false},{"text":"A period of economic recovery after the Second World War","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Enlightenment was a period during the 18th century when new ideas about politics, philosophy and science were developed."},
  {"id":"5364","question":"Which of the following charities helps the environment?","answers":[{"text":"NSPCC","correct":false},{"text":"Shelter","correct":false},{"text":"Friends of the Earth","correct":true},{"text":"Crisis","correct":false}],"explanation":"Friends of the Earth is an environmental charity."},
  {"id":"5365","question":"Which of the following was a crucial aerial battle fought between Germany and Britain during WWII?","answers":[{"text":"The Battle of Britain","correct":true},{"text":"The Battle of Worcester","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Dunbar","correct":false},{"text":"The Battle of Marston Moor","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Battle of Britain."},
  {"id":"5366","question":"What was Margaret Thatcher famous for?","answers":[{"text":"She fought for the right to vote for women","correct":false},{"text":"She was the first woman Prime Minister of the UK","correct":true},{"text":"She set up the women’s Franchise League","correct":false},{"text":"She was the founder of modern nursing","correct":false}],"explanation":"Margaret Thatcher was the first woman Prime Minister of the UK."},
  {"id":"5367","question":"Which two languages combined to become one English language?","answers":[{"text":"Latin","correct":false},{"text":"Anglo-Saxon","correct":true},{"text":"Proto-Celtic","correct":false},{"text":"Norman French","correct":true}],"explanation":"After the Norman Conquest, the king and his noblemen had spoken Norman French and the peasants had continued to speak Anglo-Saxon. Gradually these two languages combined to become one English language."},
  {"id":"5368","question":"By law, radio and television coverage of the political parties must be balanced and so equal time has to be given to rival viewpoints.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5369","question":"Where did the Spanish Armada come from?","answers":[{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Spain","correct":true},{"text":"Italy","correct":false},{"text":"South America","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1588 the English defeated the Spanish Armada (a large fleet of ships), which had been sent by Spain to conquer England and restore Catholicism."},
  {"id":"5370","question":"What is the name of the War Memorial located in Whitehall?","answers":[{"text":"Dumfries","correct":false},{"text":"Cenotaph","correct":true},{"text":"Royal Crescent","correct":false},{"text":"The White Tower","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Cenotaph is a war memorial located in Whitehall."},
  {"id":"5371","question":"The UK government has never suspended the Northern Ireland Assembly.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"False. The Northern Ireland Assembly has been suspended on a few occasions."},
  {"id":"5372","question":"Who is responsible for the opening of the new parliamentary session each year?","answers":[{"text":"The Prime Minister","correct":false},{"text":"The Speaker","correct":false},{"text":"The Queen","correct":true},{"text":"The Home Secretary","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Queen has important ceremonial roles, such as the opening of the new parliamentary session each year."},
  {"id":"5373","question":"When was the Domesday Book written?","answers":[{"text":"After the Viking invasion","correct":false},{"text":"After the Norman conquest","correct":true},{"text":"After the last Roman invasion","correct":false},{"text":"After the Anglo-Saxon invasion","correct":false}],"explanation":"William the conqueror sent people all over England to draw up lists of all the towns and villages. The people who lived there, who owned the land and what animals they owned were also listed. This was called the Domesday Book, which gives a picture of society in England just after the Norman Conquest."},
  {"id":"5374","question":"The Northern Ireland Assembly cannot make decisions on which two of the following issues?","answers":[{"text":"Immigration","correct":true},{"text":"Education","correct":false},{"text":"Agriculture","correct":false},{"text":"Defence","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Northern Ireland Assembly can make decisions on issues such as: education, agriculture, the environment health and social services, but it cannot make decisions on immigration or defence issues."},
  {"id":"5375","question":"What should you do to make a complaint about the police (choose two answers)?","answers":[{"text":"Write a complaint letter to the House of Commons","correct":false},{"text":"Go to the Police station directly","correct":true},{"text":"Write to the Chief Constable of the police force involved","correct":true},{"text":"Write to your MP","correct":false}],"explanation":"Anyone can make a complaint about the police by going to a police station and writing to the Chief Constable of the police force involved. Complaints can also be made to an independent body: the Independent Police Complaints Commission in England and Wales, the Police Complaints Commissioner for Scotland or the Police Ombudsman for Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"5376","question":"What flower did William Wordsworth write about?","answers":[{"text":"Rose","correct":false},{"text":"Daffodil","correct":true},{"text":"Thistle","correct":false},{"text":"Shamrock","correct":false}],"explanation":"William Wordsworth wrote ‘The Daffodils’."},
  {"id":"5377","question":"When is St Andrew’s day celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"17th April","correct":false},{"text":"31st December","correct":false},{"text":"1st March","correct":false},{"text":"30th November","correct":true}],"explanation":"St Andrew’s day, patron of Scotland, is celebrated on the 30th of November."},
  {"id":"5378","question":"Can the National Anthem be played if the Queen is not present?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}],"explanation":"Yes. The National Anthem is played at important national occasions and at events attended by the Queen or the Royal Family."},
  {"id":"5379","question":"When were the first coins in Britain made?","answers":[{"text":"The Stone Age","correct":false},{"text":"The Bronze Age","correct":false},{"text":"The Iron Age","correct":true},{"text":"The Middle Ages","correct":false}],"explanation":"The people of the Iron Age made the first coins to be minted in Britain."},
  {"id":"5381","question":"Who was Emmeline Pankhurst?","answers":[{"text":"A suffragette","correct":true},{"text":"A nurse","correct":false},{"text":"A doctor","correct":false},{"text":"A scientist","correct":false}],"explanation":"Emmeline Pankhurst was born in Manchester in 1858. She set up the women’s Franchise League in 1889, which fought to get the vote in local elections for married women. In 1903 she helped found the Women’s Social and Political Union (WSPU). This was the first group whose members were called ‘suffragettes’."},
  {"id":"5384","question":"Who did Britain fight against in the Crimean War?","answers":[{"text":"Turkey","correct":false},{"text":"Russia","correct":true},{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Germany","correct":false}],"explanation":"From 1853 to 1856, Britain fought with Turkey and France against Russia in the Crimean War."},
  {"id":"5386","question":"How old do you have to be to buy alcohol in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"17","correct":false},{"text":"18","correct":true},{"text":"19","correct":false},{"text":"20","correct":false}],"explanation":"It is a criminal offence to sell alcohol to anyone who is under 18 or to buy alcohol for people who are under the age of 18. (There is one exception: people aged 16 or over can drink alcohol with a meal in a hotel or restaurant)."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-practice-questions-12/
  {"id":"5441","question":"Which of the following is a Crown Dependency but not part of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Shetland","correct":false},{"text":"Isle of Wight","correct":false},{"text":"Isle of Man","correct":true},{"text":"Anglesey","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Channel Islands and the Isle of Man are closely linked with the UK but are not part of it. They have their own governments and are called ‘Crown dependencies’."},
  {"id":"5402","question":"Is the BBC controlled by the government?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}],"explanation":"The BBC is the largest broadcaster in the world. It is the only wholly state-funded media organisation that is independent of government."},
  {"id":"5403","question":"How many members does the Northern Ireland Assembly have?","answers":[{"text":"12","correct":false},{"text":"60","correct":false},{"text":"90","correct":true},{"text":"108","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Northern Ireland Assembly has 90 elected members, known as MLAs (members of the Legislative Assembly)."},
  {"id":"5404","question":"Who was in charge of the British fleet at the Battle of Trafalgar?","answers":[{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false},{"text":"The Duke of Wellington","correct":false},{"text":"Robert the Bruce","correct":false},{"text":"Admiral Nelson","correct":true}],"explanation":"Admiral Nelson was in charge of the British fleet at Trafalgar and was killed in the battle."},
  {"id":"5405","question":"What was inscribed in the first coins to be minted in Britain during the Iron Age?","answers":[{"text":"The names of Iron Age kings","correct":true},{"text":"The names of Iron Age Gods","correct":false},{"text":"The names of trees","correct":false},{"text":"The names of animals","correct":false}],"explanation":"The people of the Iron Age made the first coins to be minted in Britain, some inscribed with the names of Iron Age kings."},
  {"id":"5406","question":"Towns, cities and rural areas in the UK are governed by government appointed officials.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"Towns, cities and rural areas in the UK are governed by democratically elected councils, often called ‘local authorities’."},
  {"id":"5407","question":"Where is the Tate Art Gallery located?","answers":[{"text":"Glasgow","correct":false},{"text":"Cardiff","correct":false},{"text":"London","correct":true},{"text":"Belfast","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Tate Britain and Tate Modern are in London."},
  {"id":"5408","question":"The version of the Bible created by King James I is known as:","answers":[{"text":"Authorised version","correct":true},{"text":"Reformed version","correct":false},{"text":"Approved version","correct":false},{"text":"Unique version","correct":false}],"explanation":"One achievement of King James’ reign was a new translation of the Bible into English. This translation is known as the ‘King James Version’ or the ‘Authorised Version’."},
  {"id":"5409","question":"What is the period of the 1960s known for?","answers":[{"text":"A downgrade in manufacturing","correct":false},{"text":"A growth in British fashion and pop music","correct":true},{"text":"A shortage of water","correct":false},{"text":"A blockage of social laws","correct":false}],"explanation":""},
  {"id":"5437","question":"Between 1680 and 1720 many refugees called Huguenots came to England, which country did they come from?","answers":[{"text":"Pakistan","correct":false},{"text":"Germany","correct":false},{"text":"India","correct":false},{"text":"France","correct":true}],"explanation":"Between 1680 and 1720 many refugees called Huguenots came from France."},
  {"id":"5419","question":"What is the most famous tennis tournament played in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"The Queen's Club Championships","correct":false},{"text":"Wimbledon","correct":true},{"text":"Roland Garros","correct":false},{"text":"The Aegon Championships","correct":false}],"explanation":"The most famous tournament hosted in Britain is The Wimbledon Championships, which takes place each year at the All England Lawn Tennis and Croquet Club."},
  {"id":"5420","question":"MPs can only be contacted at their office in the House of Commons.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"You can contact MPs by letter or telephone at their constituency office, or at their office in the House of Commons. In addition, many MPs, Assembly members, MSPs and MEPs hold regular local ‘surgeries’, where constituents can go in person to talk about issues that are of concern to them."},
  {"id":"5421","question":"What is the day when jokes are published in newspapers and telecasted on TV?","answers":[{"text":"April Fool’s Day","correct":true},{"text":"Boxing Day","correct":false},{"text":"Halloween","correct":false},{"text":"Valentine’s Day","correct":false}],"explanation":"April Fool’s Day, 1 April, is a day when people play jokes on each other until midday. The television and newspapers often have stories that are April Fool jokes."},
  {"id":"5422","question":"Which Scottish king defeated the English at the Battle of Bannockburn?","answers":[{"text":"King Charles I","correct":false},{"text":"King James I","correct":false},{"text":"Admiral Nelson","correct":false},{"text":"Robert the Bruce","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 1314 the Scottish, led by Robert the Bruce, defeated the English at the Battle of Bannockburn, and Scotland remained unconquered by the English."},
  {"id":"5423","question":"Who invented the World Wide Web?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Tim Berners-Lee","correct":true},{"text":"Sir Peter Mansfield","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Ian Wilmot","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Robert Edwards","correct":false}],"explanation":"The inventor of the World Wide Web was Sir Tim Berners-Lee."},
  {"id":"5424","question":"How are civil servants appointed and what political party do they belong to?","answers":[{"text":"They are chosen on merit and form part of the Liberal Democrats party","correct":false},{"text":"They are chosen randomly and form part of the Conservative party","correct":false},{"text":"They are chosen randomly and are politically neutral","correct":false},{"text":"They are chosen on merit and are politically neutral","correct":true}],"explanation":"Civil servants are chosen on merit and are politically neutral – they are not political appointees."},
  {"id":"5425","question":"What is known as the “Dunkirk spirit”?","answers":[{"text":"When the German air force bombed London and other British cities at night-time","correct":false},{"text":"The evacuation of Allied soldiers from France during World War II","correct":true},{"text":"When new social classes appeared after the Black Death","correct":false},{"text":"The period when many refugees called Huguenots came from France","correct":false}],"explanation":"During WWII as France fell, the British decided to evacuate British and French soldiers from France in a huge naval operation. Many civilian volunteers in small pleasure and fishing boats from Britain helped the Navy to rescue more than 300,000 men from the beaches around Dunkirk."},
  {"id":"5430","question":"You have to be at least 21 years old to serve on a jury.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"Anyone who is on the electoral register and is aged 18 to 70 can serve on a jury."},
  {"id":"5431","question":"If you wish to be a permanent resident or citizen of the UK, you should (choose TWO answers):\n\n","answers":[{"text":"Respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions","correct":true},{"text":"Buy a house in the UK","correct":false},{"text":"Look after yourself and your family","correct":true},{"text":"Marry a British citizen","correct":false}],"explanation":"If you wish to be a permanent resident or citizen of the UK, you should: respect the rights of others, including their right to their own opinions, look after yourself and your family, respect and obey the law, treat others with fairness and look after the area in which you live and the environment."},
  {"id":"5432","question":"Which of the following major sports event took place in the UK in 2012?","answers":[{"text":"The Football World Cup","correct":false},{"text":"The Rugby World Cup","correct":false},{"text":"The Olympic games","correct":true},{"text":"The Eurocup Basketball","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UK has hosted the Olympic games on three occasions: 1908, 1948 and 2012."},
  {"id":"5433","question":"Charles I believed in the ‘Divine Right of Kings’ so he tried:","answers":[{"text":"To rule without the Parliament","correct":true},{"text":"To rule with the approval of the Parliament","correct":false},{"text":"To raise money for the Parliament","correct":false},{"text":"To restore Catholicism in Britain","correct":false}],"explanation":"Charles I believed in the ‘Divine Right of Kings’: the idea that the king was directly appointed by God to rule. He thought that the king should be able to act without having to seek approval from Parliament and he tried to rule without the Parliament at all."},
  {"id":"5434","question":"What is the Union Jack?","answers":[{"text":"The Flag of the Commonwealth","correct":false},{"text":"The Flag of the United Kingdom","correct":true},{"text":"The shield used by British Knights","correct":false},{"text":"A trade union to protect workers rights","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Union Flag is also known as the Union Jack."},
  {"id":"5435","question":"Who was voted the greatest Briton of all time in 2002?","answers":[{"text":"Mo Farah","correct":false},{"text":"Admiral Nelson","correct":false},{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":true},{"text":"Clement Attlee","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 2002 Winston Churchill was voted the greatest Briton of all time by the public."},
  {"id":"5436","question":"Which of the following statements is true:","answers":[{"text":"Women in Britain today make up about half of the workforce.","correct":true},{"text":"Women in Britain today make up about one quarter of the workforce.","correct":false}],"explanation":"Women in Britain today make up about half of the workforce."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-13/
  {"id":"5466","question":"When is St George’s day?","answers":[{"text":"17th March","correct":false},{"text":"30th November","correct":false},{"text":"1st March","correct":false},{"text":"23rd April","correct":true}],"explanation":"St George’s day, patron of England is celebrated on the 23rd of April."},
  {"id":"5467","question":"Which is the largest National Park in England?","answers":[{"text":"Snowdonia","correct":false},{"text":"Loch Lomond and the Trossachs National Park","correct":false},{"text":"The Giant’s Causeway","correct":false},{"text":"The Lake District","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Lake District is England’s largest national park."},
  {"id":"5468","question":"Boudicca, was a tribal leader who fought against which foreign invaders?","answers":[{"text":"The Normands","correct":false},{"text":"The Vikings","correct":false},{"text":"The Anglo-Saxons","correct":false},{"text":"The Romans","correct":true}],"explanation":"One of the tribal leaders who fought against the Romans was Boudicca, the queen of the Iceni."},
  {"id":"5469","question":"Which of the following poems is about a group of people going on a pilgrimage?","answers":[{"text":"The Canterbury Tales","correct":true},{"text":"All the world’s a stage","correct":false},{"text":"A Midsummer Night’s dream","correct":false},{"text":"Great Expectations","correct":false}],"explanation":"Geoffrey Chaucer wrote a series of poems in English about a group of people going to Canterbury on a pilgrimage. The people decided to tell each other stories on the journey, and the poems describe the travellers and some of the stories they told. This collection of poems is called The Canterbury Tales."},
  {"id":"5470","question":"How are public holidays called?","answers":[{"text":"Bank Holidays","correct":true},{"text":"Workers Holidays","correct":false},{"text":"Business Holidays","correct":false},{"text":"Summer Holidays","correct":false}],"explanation":"There are public holidays each year called bank holidays, when banks and many other businesses are closed for the day."},
  {"id":"5471","question":"How did Charles II manage to escape to Europe after his defeat in the Civil War?","answers":[{"text":"Hiding in a farmer's house","correct":false},{"text":"Riding a horse","correct":false},{"text":"Hiding in an oak tree","correct":true},{"text":"Swimming","correct":false}],"explanation":"Charles II escaped from Worcester, famously hiding in an oak tree on one occasion, and eventually fled to Europe."},
  {"id":"5472","question":"Who defeated the Vikings?","answers":[{"text":"Harold","correct":false},{"text":"Edward I of England","correct":false},{"text":"King Arthur","correct":false},{"text":"King Alfred the Great","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Anglo-Saxon kingdoms in England united under King Alfred the Great, who defeated the Vikings."},
  {"id":"5473","question":"Who was William Caxton?","answers":[{"text":"A poet who wrote about a group of people going to Canterbury on a pilgrimage","correct":false},{"text":"The first person in England to print books using a printing press","correct":true},{"text":"The first person to sail singlehanded around the world","correct":false},{"text":"The inventor of the television","correct":false}],"explanation":"William Caxton was the first person in England to print books using a printing press."},
  {"id":"5474","question":"Where do Beefeaters serve as tour guides?","answers":[{"text":"The Houses of the Parliament","correct":false},{"text":"The Tower of London","correct":true},{"text":"The O2","correct":false},{"text":"The Big Ben","correct":false}],"explanation":"Beefeaters serve as tour guides at the Tower of London."},
  {"id":"5475","question":"During the rebellion of the clans in Scotland, Bonnie Prince Charlie was supported by clansmen from which Scottish region?","answers":[{"text":"Glasgow","correct":false},{"text":"Galloway","correct":false},{"text":"Highlands","correct":true},{"text":"Edinburgh","correct":false}],"explanation":"Charles Edward Stuart (Bonnie Prince Charlie) was supported by clansmen from the Scottish highlands."},
  {"id":"5476","question":"What religion did Elizabeth I follow?","answers":[{"text":"She was a Protestant","correct":true},{"text":"She was a Catholic","correct":false}],"explanation":"Elizabeth the I was a protestant."},
  {"id":"5477","question":"Who became famous for his tramp character in silent movies?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Rex Harrison","correct":false},{"text":"David Niven","correct":false},{"text":"Richard Burton","correct":false},{"text":"Charlie Chaplin","correct":true}],"explanation":"Charlie Chaplin became famous in silent movies for his tramp character."},
  {"id":"5478","question":"Which armed force was used in the Battle of Britain?","answers":[{"text":"The Royal Navy","correct":false},{"text":"The Police Force","correct":false},{"text":"The Naval Service","correct":false},{"text":"The Royal Air Force","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Royal Air Force."},
  {"id":"5479","question":"In the UK, you have to be 21 years old to be able to vote in a general election.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"The present voting age of 18 was set in 1969 and (with a few exceptions) all UK-born and naturalised adult citizens have the right to vote."},
  {"id":"5480","question":"Which of the following poets was inspired by nature? ","answers":[{"text":"John Masefield","correct":false},{"text":"Wilfred Owen","correct":false},{"text":"Siegfried Sassoon","correct":false},{"text":"William Wordsworth","correct":true}],"explanation":"British poets, including William Wordsworth, were inspired by nature."},
  {"id":"5481","question":"Against which country did Britain fight at the Battle of Waterloo?","answers":[{"text":"Germany","correct":false},{"text":"Italy","correct":false},{"text":"France","correct":true},{"text":"Spain","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1815, the French Wars ended with the defeat of the Emperor Napoleon by the Duke of Wellington at the Battle of Waterloo."},
  {"id":"5482","question":"Who was William Wilberforce?","answers":[{"text":"A poet","correct":false},{"text":"A sportsman","correct":false},{"text":"A politician","correct":true},{"text":"A musician","correct":false}],"explanation":"William Wilberforce, an evangelical Christian and a member of Parliament, also played an important part in changing the law. Along with other abolitionists (people who supported the abolition of slavery), he succeeded in turning public opinion against the slave trade."},
  {"id":"5483","question":"Who is the spiritual leader of the Church of England?","answers":[{"text":"The Archbishop of Canterbury","correct":true},{"text":"The Archbishop of London","correct":false},{"text":"The Archbishop of Birmingham","correct":false},{"text":"The Archbishop of Manchester","correct":false}],"explanation":"The spiritual leader of the Church of England is the Archbishop of Canterbury."},
  {"id":"5484","question":"James I was King of which country before becoming King of England?","answers":[{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":true}],"explanation":"When Elizabeth I died, her cousin James VI of Scotland became King James I of England, Wales and Ireland and Scotland remained a separate country."},
  {"id":"5485","question":"Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"text":"Most shops in the UK open seven days a week.","correct":true},{"text":"All shops in the UK close on Sundays and bank holidays.","correct":false}],"explanation":"Most shops in the UK are open seven days a week, although trading hours on Sundays and public holidays are generally reduced."},
  {"id":"5486","question":"Which country sent a fleet of ships to England in 1588?","answers":[{"text":"France","correct":false},{"text":"Germany","correct":false},{"text":"Spain","correct":true},{"text":"Italy","correct":false}],"explanation":"Elizabeth became one of the most popular monarchs in English history, particularly after 1588, when the English defeated the Spanish Armada (a large fleet of ships), which had been sent by Spain to conquer England and restore Catholicism."},
  {"id":"5487","question":"Where is the National Horseracing Museum located?","answers":[{"text":"Edinburgh, Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Newmarket, Suffolk","correct":true},{"text":"St Andrews, Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"Aintree near Liverpool","correct":false}],"explanation":"There is a National Horseracing Museum in Newmarket, Suffolk."},
  {"id":"5488","question":"Which of the following castles is located in Scotland?","answers":[{"text":"Crathes Castle","correct":true},{"text":"Caernarfon Castle","correct":false},{"text":"Bodiam Castle","correct":false},{"text":"Powis Castle","correct":false}],"explanation":"Crathes Castle is located in Scotland."},
  {"id":"5607","question":"Who was a famous Art Deco ceramic designer?","answers":[{"text":"Alexander McQueen","correct":false},{"text":"Thomas Chippendale","correct":false},{"text":"Clarice Cliff","correct":true},{"text":"Mary Quant","correct":false}],"explanation":"Britain has produced many great designers, from Thomas Chippendale (who designed furniture in the 18th century) to Clarice Cliff (who designed Art Deco ceramics) to Sir Terence Conran (a 20th-century interior designer)."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-14/
  {"id":"5583","question":"When is St Patrick’s day celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"23rd April","correct":false},{"text":"30th November","correct":false},{"text":"1st April","correct":false},{"text":"17th March","correct":true}],"explanation":"St Patrick’s day, patron of Northern Ireland is celebrated on the 17th of March."},
  {"id":"5584","question":"How are the members of the Northern Ireland Parliament elected?","answers":[{"text":"By a system of proportional representation","correct":true},{"text":"Using a system of ranked voting","correct":false},{"text":"Using the first past the post system","correct":false},{"text":"Using a runoff system","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Northern Ireland Assembly has 108 elected members, known as MLAs (members of the Legislative Assembly). They are elected with a form of proportional representation."},
  {"id":"5585","question":"Who was the first British Prime Minister?","answers":[{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":false},{"text":"Earl of Wilmington","correct":false},{"text":"Henry Pelham","correct":false},{"text":"Sir Robert Walpole","correct":true}],"explanation":"The most important minister in Parliament became known as the Prime Minister. The first man to be called this was Sir Robert Walpole, who was Prime Minister from 1721 to 1742."},
  {"id":"5586","question":"Which of the following actresses has not won an Oscar?","answers":[{"text":"Tilda Swinton","correct":false},{"text":"Emily Watson","correct":true},{"text":"Dame Judi Dench","correct":false},{"text":"Kate Winslet","correct":false}],"explanation":"British actors to have won Oscars include Colin Firth, Sir Antony Hopkins, Dame Judi Dench, Kate Winslet and Tilda Swinton. Emily Watson has not won an Oscar yet."},
  {"id":"5587","question":"During the Enlightenment, Adam Smith developed ideas about:","answers":[{"text":"Physics","correct":false},{"text":"Economics","correct":true},{"text":"Science","correct":false},{"text":"Engineering","correct":false}],"explanation":"During ‘the Enlightenment’ Adam Smith developed ideas about economics which are still referred to today."},
  {"id":"5589","question":"Who died at the Battle of Trafalgar?","answers":[{"text":"Admiral Nelson","correct":true},{"text":"Henry VIII","correct":false},{"text":"Oliver Cromwell","correct":false},{"text":"Napoleon","correct":false}],"explanation":"Admiral Nelson was in charge of the British fleet at Trafalgar and was killed in the battle."},
  {"id":"5590","question":"When is Hogmanay celebrated?","answers":[{"text":"25th of December","correct":false},{"text":"2nd of January","correct":false},{"text":"1st of January","correct":false},{"text":"31st of December","correct":true}],"explanation":"In Scotland, the 31st of December is called Hogmanay."},
  {"id":"5591","question":"Proceedings in Parliament are broadcast on television and published in official reports known as:\n\n","answers":[{"text":"Canvassing","correct":false},{"text":"Hansard","correct":true},{"text":"Cabinets","correct":false},{"text":"Domesday Book","correct":false}],"explanation":"Proceedings in Parliament are broadcast on television and published in official reports called Hansard."},
  {"id":"5592","question":"Which of the following is a rugby competition?","answers":[{"text":"The Scottish Grand National","correct":false},{"text":"The Wimbledon Championships","correct":false},{"text":"The Ashes","correct":false},{"text":"The Six Nations Championship","correct":true}],"explanation":"The most famous rugby union competition is the Six Nations Championship between England, Ireland, Scotland, Wales, France and Italy."},
  {"id":"5593","question":"Who appoints life peers in the House of Lords?","answers":[{"text":"The Speaker","correct":false},{"text":"The Archbishop of Canterbury","correct":false},{"text":"The Prime Minister","correct":false},{"text":"The monarch","correct":true}],"explanation":"Life peers are appointed by the monarch on the advice of the Prime Minister."},
  {"id":"5594","question":"Who mapped the coast of Australia?","answers":[{"text":"James Cook","correct":true},{"text":"Admiral Nelson","correct":false},{"text":"Isaac Newton","correct":false},{"text":"Sake Dean Mahomet","correct":false}],"explanation":"Captain James Cook mapped the coast of Australia and a few colonies were established there."},
  {"id":"5595","question":"What was the first war to be extensively covered by the media?","answers":[{"text":"The Boer War","correct":false},{"text":"The First World War","correct":false},{"text":"The Second World War","correct":false},{"text":"The Crimean War","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Crimean War was the first war to be extensively covered by the media through news stories and photographs."},
  {"id":"5596","question":"Which of the following monuments is located in Wiltshire?","answers":[{"text":"Hadrian’s Wall","correct":false},{"text":"St Paul’s Cathedral","correct":false},{"text":"Nelson’s Column","correct":false},{"text":"Stonehenge","correct":true}],"explanation":"Stonehenge stands in what is now the English county of Wiltshire."},
  {"id":"5597","question":"Who was the first Archbishop of Canterbury?","answers":[{"text":"St Patrick","correct":false},{"text":"St Augustine","correct":true},{"text":"St Andrew","correct":false},{"text":"St Columba","correct":false}],"explanation":"St Augustine led missionaries from Rome, who spread Christianity in the south. St Augustine became the first Archbishop of Canterbury."},
  {"id":"5598","question":"How old do you have to be to go into betting shops or gambling clubs?","answers":[{"text":"18","correct":true},{"text":"20","correct":false},{"text":"16","correct":false},{"text":"21","correct":false}],"explanation":"You have to be 18 to go into betting shops or gambling clubs."},
  {"id":"5599","question":"The system of government in the UK is a parliamentary democracy.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"This statement is true."},
  {"id":"5600","question":"What is the traditional food of Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"Haggis","correct":false},{"text":"Pancakes","correct":false},{"text":"Paella","correct":false},{"text":"Ulster Fry","correct":true}],"explanation":"Ulster fry is the correct answer."},
  {"id":"5601","question":"Who was elected as British Prime Minister in 1945?","answers":[{"text":"Clement Attlee","correct":true},{"text":"Winston Churchill","correct":false},{"text":"Harold Wilson","correct":false},{"text":"Harold Macmillan","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1945 the British people elected a Labour government. The new Prime Minister was Clement Attlee."},
  {"id":"5602","question":"How many times has the UK hosted the Olympic games?","answers":[{"text":"5","correct":false},{"text":"3","correct":true},{"text":"4","correct":false},{"text":"8","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UK has hosted the Olympic games on three occasions: 1908, 1948 and 2012."},
  {"id":"5603","question":"Why were canals built during the Industrial Revolution?","answers":[{"text":"To link the factories to towns and cities and to the ports","correct":true},{"text":"To make space for the large fleet of British ships","correct":false},{"text":"To increase the number of water mills in the UK","correct":false},{"text":"To increase the amount of water in towns and cities","correct":false}],"explanation":"Canals were built to link the factories to towns and cities and to the ports, particularly in the new industrial areas in the middle and north of England."},
  {"id":"5604","question":"Are civil servants appointed by the government?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}],"explanation":"Civil servants are accountable to ministers. They are chosen on merit and are politically neutral – they are not political appointees."},
  {"id":"5605","question":"Which of the following countries helped Britain to develop the Concorde?","answers":[{"text":"Germany","correct":false},{"text":"Norway","correct":false},{"text":"Italy","correct":false},{"text":"France","correct":true}],"explanation":"Britain and France developed the world’s only supersonic commercial airliner, Concorde."},
  {"id":"5606","question":"Which invention led to the development of Britain during the Industrial Revolution?","answers":[{"text":"Magnetic Resonance Imaging","correct":false},{"text":"Steam power","correct":true},{"text":"Radar","correct":false},{"text":"Hovercraft","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Industrial Revolution was the rapid development of industry in Britain in the 18th and 19th centuries. Britain was the first country to industrialise on a large scale. It happened because of the development of machinery and the use of steam power."},
  {"id":"5608","question":"Who was the tribal leader who fought against the Romans?","answers":[{"text":"Columba","correct":false},{"text":"Claudius","correct":false},{"text":"Hadrian","correct":false},{"text":"Boudicca","correct":true}],"explanation":"One of the tribal leaders who fought against the Romans was Boudicca."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/british-citizenship-test-15/
  {"id":"5995","question":"Which two languages were used across England during the Middle Ages?","answers":[{"text":"Welsh","correct":false},{"text":"Gaelic","correct":false},{"text":"Norman French","correct":true},{"text":"Anglo-Saxon","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Middle Ages saw the development of a national culture and identity. After the Norman Conquest, the king and his noblemen had spoken Norman French and the peasants had continued to speak Anglo-Saxon."},
  {"id":"5996","question":"In 1776, which British colonies declared their independence because they demanded that there should be ‘no taxation without representation’.","answers":[{"text":"North African","correct":false},{"text":"Asian","correct":false},{"text":"North American","correct":true},{"text":"South African","correct":false}],"explanation":"In 1776, 13 American colonies declared their independence, stating that people had a right to establish their own governments."},
  {"id":"5997","question":"When was England ruled by a republic and not by a monarch?","answers":[{"text":"When Elizabeth I died without any successor","correct":false},{"text":"When Charles I was executed","correct":true},{"text":"When the Carta Magna restricted the king’s power","correct":false},{"text":"When kind Harold died after the Battle of Hastings","correct":false}],"explanation":"When Charles I was executed, England declared itself a republic, called the Commonwealth. It no longer had a monarch."},
  {"id":"5998","question":"Which film produced in the UK was one of the most commercially successful films of all time and one of the highest-grossing film franchises?","answers":[{"text":"Harry Potter","correct":true},{"text":"Spider-man","correct":false},{"text":"The Lord of the Rings","correct":false},{"text":"Indiana Jones","correct":false}],"explanation":"Some of the most commercially successful films of all time, including the two highest-grossing film franchises (Harry Potter and James Bond), have been produced in the UK."},
  {"id":"5999","question":"When did the first farmers come to Britain?","answers":[{"text":"10,000 years ago","correct":false},{"text":"6,000 years ago","correct":true},{"text":"15,000 years ago","correct":false},{"text":"2,000 years ago","correct":false}],"explanation":"The first farmers arrived in Britain 6,000 years ago."},
  {"id":"6000","question":"When did the First World War end?","answers":[{"text":"At 12.00 pm on 11th November 1914","correct":false},{"text":"At 12.00 pm on 11th November 1918","correct":false},{"text":"At 11.00 am on 11th November 1914","correct":false},{"text":"At 11.00 am on 11th November 1918","correct":true}],"explanation":"The First World War ended at 11.00 am on 11th November 1918 with victory for Britain and its allies."},
  {"id":"6001","question":"Can court orders be obtained to protect a person from being forced into a marriage?","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}],"explanation":"Court orders can be obtained to protect a person from being forced into a marriage, or to protect a person in a forced marriage."},
  {"id":"6002","question":"What medal did Mary Peters win in the 1972 Olympics?","answers":[{"text":"She did not win any medals","correct":false},{"text":"Silver","correct":false},{"text":"Gold","correct":true},{"text":"Bronze","correct":false}],"explanation":"Born in Manchester, Mary Peters moved to Northern Ireland as a child. She was a talented athlete who won an Olympic gold medal in the pentathlon in 1972."},
  {"id":"6003","question":"In England, Wales and Northern Ireland Youth Court cases are normally heard by (choose TWO answers)?","answers":[{"text":"Up to 3 specially trained magistrates","correct":true},{"text":"A District Judge","correct":true},{"text":"A sheriff","correct":false},{"text":"Up to 5 specially trained magistrates","correct":false}],"explanation":"In England, Wales and Northern Ireland, if an accused person is aged 10 to 17, the case is normally heard in a Youth Court in front of up to three specially trained magistrates or a District Judge."},
  {"id":"6004","question":"What was invented by Alan Turing in the 1930s?","answers":[{"text":"The jet engine","correct":false},{"text":"The television","correct":false},{"text":"The Turing machine","correct":true},{"text":"The ball pen","correct":false}],"explanation":"A Turing machine is a theoretical mathematical device invented by Alan Turing (1912-54), a British mathematician, in the 1930s."},
  {"id":"6005","question":"Which of the following tells us about how people lived in England just after the Norman Conquest?","answers":[{"text":"The Domesday Book","correct":true},{"text":"The Book of Common Prayer","correct":false},{"text":"The Canterbury Tales","correct":false},{"text":"The Carta Magna","correct":false}],"explanation":"William sent people all over England to draw up lists of all the towns and villages. The people who lived there, who owned the land and what animals they owned were also listed. This was called the Domesday Book. It still exists today and gives a picture of society in England just after the Norman Conquest."},
  {"id":"6006","question":"Who led a team of scientists to ‘split the atom’ for the first time?","answers":[{"text":"Alexander Fleming","correct":false},{"text":"Alan Turing","correct":false},{"text":"Ernest Rutherford","correct":true},{"text":"Sir Peter Mansfield","correct":false}],"explanation":"Scientists led by Ernest Rutherford, working at Manchester and then Cambridge University, were the first to ‘split the atom’ and took part in the Manhattan Project in the United States, which developed the atomic bomb."},
  {"id":"6008","question":"What song is sung by people in the UK and other countries when they are celebrating the New Year?","answers":[{"text":"Auld Lang Syne","correct":true},{"text":"The British Anthem","correct":false},{"text":"Jingle Bells","correct":false},{"text":"White Christmas","correct":false}],"explanation":"The song Auld Lang Syne, which is sung by people in the UK and other countries when they are celebrating the New Year (or Hogmanay as it is called in Scotland)."},
  {"id":"6009","question":"Who fought in the English Civil war of 1642?","answers":[{"text":"The House of York and the House of Lancaster","correct":false},{"text":"The Anglo-Saxons and the Vikings","correct":false},{"text":"The Cavaliers and the Roundheads","correct":true},{"text":"The House of Fraser and the House of Stuart","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Civil war between the king and Parliament began in 1642. The country split into those who supported the king (the Cavaliers) and those who supported Parliament (the Roundheads)."},
  {"id":"6010","question":"Which two of these forts were part of Hadrian’s wall?","answers":[{"text":"Vindolanda","correct":true},{"text":"Maiden Castle","correct":false},{"text":"Housesteads","correct":true},{"text":"Grimsby","correct":false}],"explanation":"Parts of Hadrian’s Wall, include the forts of Housesteads and Vindolanda."},
  {"id":"6011","question":"What was the religion of the Puritans?","answers":[{"text":"Hindu","correct":false},{"text":"Catholic","correct":false},{"text":"Sikh","correct":false},{"text":"Protestant","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Puritans were a group of Protestants who advocated strict and simple religious doctrine and worship."},
  {"id":"6012","question":"What is the name of Irish people who favoured complete independence from the UK in the 19th century?","answers":[{"text":"Fenians","correct":true},{"text":"Quakers","correct":false},{"text":"Highlanders","correct":false},{"text":"Suffragettes","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Irish Nationalist movement had grown strongly through the 19th century. Some, such as the Fenians, favoured complete independence."},
  {"id":"6013","question":"Which two British pop music groups were famous during the Swinging Sixties?","answers":[{"text":"The Rolling Stones","correct":true},{"text":"The Beatles","correct":true},{"text":"ABBA","correct":false},{"text":"Radiohead","correct":false}],"explanation":"The decade of the 1960s was a period of significant social change. It was known as the ‘swinging sixties’. There was growth in British fashion, cinema and popular music. Two well-known pop music groups at the time were The Beatles and The Rolling Stones."},
  {"id":"6014","question":"What is the minimum age required to drive a motorcycle?","answers":[{"text":"16 years old","correct":false},{"text":"17 years old","correct":true},{"text":"18 years old","correct":false},{"text":"21 years old","correct":false}],"explanation":"In the UK, you must be at least 17 years to drive a car or motorcycle and you must have a driving licence to drive on public roads."},
  {"id":"6015","question":"The members of the House of Lords, known as peers, are elected by the people.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}],"explanation":"The members of the House of Lords, known as peers, are not elected by the people."},
  {"id":"6016","question":"When did the Emancipation Act abolish slavery throughout the British Empire?","answers":[{"text":"1835","correct":false},{"text":"1823","correct":false},{"text":"1807","correct":false},{"text":"1833","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 1833 the Emancipation Act abolished slavery throughout the British Empire."},
  {"id":"6017","question":"Who is responsible for crime, policing and immigration?","answers":[{"text":"The Chancellor of the Exchequer","correct":false},{"text":"The Foreign Secretary","correct":false},{"text":"The Speaker","correct":false},{"text":"The Home Secretary","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Home Secretary is responsible for crime, policing and immigration."},
  {"id":"6018","question":"What kind of genre was the film Wallace and Gromit created by Nick Park?","answers":[{"text":"A soap opera","correct":false},{"text":"A silent movie","correct":false},{"text":"An animated film","correct":true},{"text":"An action film","correct":false}],"explanation":"Nick Park won four Oscars for his animated films, including three for films featuring Wallace and Gromit."},
  {"id":"6020","question":"Anyone who is violent towards their partner – whether they are a man or a woman, married or living together – can be prosecuted.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}],"explanation":"Anyone who is violent towards their partner – whether they are a man or a woman, married or living together – can be prosecuted."},

// https://lifeintheuktestweb.co.uk/life-in-the-uk-exam-16/
  {"id":"6717","question":"When was the United Nations set up?","answers":[{"text":"After the First World War.","correct":false},{"text":"After the Second World War.","correct":true},{"text":"Before the First World War.","correct":false},{"text":"Before the Second World War.","correct":false}],"explanation":"The UN was set up after the Second World War and aims to prevent war and promote international peace and security."},
  {"id":"6718","question":"Where is the Giant’s Causeway located?","answers":[{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"England","correct":false},{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Giant’s Causeway is a land formation of columns made from volcanic lava located on the north-east coast of Northern Ireland. It was formed about 50 million years ago. There are many legends about the Causeway and how it was formed."},
  {"id":"6719","question":"What happened to Mary, Queen of Scots, after being sent to prison for 20 years by her cousin Queen Elizabeth I? ","answers":[{"text":"She got married.","correct":false},{"text":"She was sent to France.","correct":false},{"text":"She was executed.","correct":true},{"text":"She was sent to Scotland.","correct":false}],"explanation":"Mary was executed, accused of plotting against Elizabeth I."},
  {"id":"6720","question":"What is the Queen’s speech about during the opening of the UK Parliament?","answers":[{"text":"What the Royal family did the previous year.","correct":false},{"text":"What the Government did the previous year.","correct":false},{"text":"What business matters the Royal family will conduct in the year ahead.","correct":false},{"text":"What the Government policies will be in the year ahead.","correct":true}],"explanation":"The Queen has important ceremonial roles, such as the opening of the new parliamentary session each year. On this occasion the Queen makes a speech which summarises the government’s policies for the year ahead. All Acts of Parliament are made in her name."},
  {"id":"6721","question":"What is one of the highest-grossing film franchises produced in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"James Bond","correct":true},{"text":"Star Wars","correct":false},{"text":"The Lord of the Rings","correct":false},{"text":"Superman","correct":false}],"explanation":"Some of the most commercially successful films of all time, including the two highest-grossing film franchises (Harry Potter and James Bond), have been produced in the UK."},
  {"id":"6722","question":"Who can hear cases in Youth Courts in England, Wales and Northern Ireland (two answers)?","answers":[{"text":"Specially trained magistrates.","correct":true},{"text":"Social workers.","correct":false},{"text":"District judges.","correct":true},{"text":"Members of the public.","correct":false}],"explanation":"In England, Wales and Northern Ireland, if an accused person is aged 10 to 17, the case is normally heard in a Youth Court in front of up to three specially trained magistrates or a District Judge. The most serious cases will go the Crown Court. The parents or carers of the young person are expected to attend the hearing. Members of the public are not allowed in Youth Courts, and the name or photographs of the accused young person cannot be published in newspapers or used by the media."},
  {"id":"6723","question":"Who came from the Netherlands to become the British monarch?","answers":[{"text":"William II","correct":false},{"text":"Charles II","correct":true},{"text":"Edward II","correct":false},{"text":"George II","correct":false}],"explanation":"In May 1660, Parliament invited Charles II to come back from exile in the Netherlands. He was crowned King Charles II of England, Wales, Scotland and Ireland."},
  {"id":"6724","question":"Who can apply for the National Citizen Service programme?","answers":[{"text":"14- and 15-year-olds","correct":false},{"text":"15- and 16-year-olds","correct":false},{"text":"16- and 17-year-olds","correct":true},{"text":"17- and 18-year-olds","correct":false}],"explanation":"The National Citizen Service programme gives 16- and 17-year-olds the opportunity to enjoy outdoor activities, develop their skills and take part in a community project."},
  {"id":"6725","question":"Nick Park has won four Oscars for his animated films, including three for films featuring:","answers":[{"text":"Chariots of Fire","correct":false},{"text":"Wallace and Gromit","correct":true},{"text":"Four Weddings and a Funeral","correct":false},{"text":"Women in Love","correct":false}],"explanation":"Nick Park, who has won four Oscars for his animated films, including three for films featuring Wallace and Gromit."},
  {"id":"6726","question":"Who was the British scientist who co-discovered the structure of the DNA molecule in the 1950s?","answers":[{"text":"Sir Ian Wilmot","correct":false},{"text":"Keith Campbell","correct":false},{"text":"James Watt","correct":false},{"text":"Francis Crick","correct":true}],"explanation":"The structure of the DNA molecule was discovered in 1953 through work at British universities in London and Cambridge. This discovery contributed to many scientific advances, particularly in medicine and fighting crime. Francis Crick (1916-2004), was one of those awarded the Nobel Prize for this discovery."},
  {"id":"6727","question":"What percentage of the UK population has a parent or grandparent born outside of the UK?","answers":[{"text":"Around 5%","correct":false},{"text":"Around 10%","correct":true},{"text":"Around 15%","correct":false},{"text":"Around 20%","correct":false}],"explanation":"Nearly 10% of the population has a parent or grandparent born outside the UK."},
  {"id":"6728","question":"How old do you have to be to drive a moped in the UK?","answers":[{"text":"15 years old","correct":false},{"text":"16 years old","correct":true},{"text":"17 years old","correct":false},{"text":"18 years old","correct":false}],"explanation":"In the UK, you need to be at least 16 years old to ride a moped, and there are other age requirements and special tests for driving large vehicles."},
  {"id":"6729","question":"Who was the leader of the Labour Party who introduced a Scottish Parliament and a Welsh Assembly?","answers":[{"text":"James Callaghan","correct":false},{"text":"Clement Attlee","correct":false},{"text":"Gordon Brown","correct":false},{"text":"Tony Blair","correct":true}],"explanation":"In 1997 the Labour Party led by Tony Blair was elected. The Blair government introduced a Scottish Parliament and a Welsh Assembly."},
  {"id":"6730","question":"What is the maximum amount you can claim through the small claims procedure in Scotland and Northern Ireland?","answers":[{"text":"£3,000","correct":true},{"text":"£5,000","correct":false},{"text":"£8,000","correct":false},{"text":"£10,000","correct":false}],"explanation":"The small claims procedure is an informal way of helping people to settle minor disputes without spending a lot of time and money using a lawyer. This procedure is used for claims of less than £10,000 in England and Wales and £3,000 in Scotland and Northern Ireland."},
  {"id":"6731","question":"Which historical monument did William the Conqueror build?","answers":[{"text":"St Paul’s Cathedral","correct":false},{"text":"The Cenotaph","correct":false},{"text":"Dumfries House","correct":false},{"text":"The White Tower","correct":true}],"explanation":"The White Tower in the Tower of London is an example of a Norman castle keep, built on the orders of William the Conqueror."},
  {"id":"6732","question":"Who became Prime Minister after Margaret Thatcher and played an important part in the Northern Ireland peace process?","answers":[{"text":"James Callaghan","correct":false},{"text":"John Major","correct":true},{"text":"Tony Blair","correct":false},{"text":"Harold Wilson","correct":false}],"explanation":"John Major was Prime Minister after Mrs Thatcher, and helped establish the Northern Ireland peace process."},
  {"id":"6733","question":"Who should you contact to report a terrorist activity?","answers":[{"text":"Your local Council.","correct":false},{"text":"Your local MP.","correct":false},{"text":"Your local police force.","correct":true},{"text":"The Prime Minister.","correct":false}],"explanation":"If you think someone is trying to persuade you to join an extremist or terrorist cause, you should notify your local police force."},
  {"id":"6734","question":"Which Paralympic athlete has won gold medals for swimming at the 2008, 2012 and 2016 Paralympic Games?","answers":[{"text":"Sophie Christiansen","correct":false},{"text":"Ellie Simmonds","correct":true},{"text":"Baroness Tanni Grey-Thompson","correct":false},{"text":"David Weir","correct":false}],"explanation":"Ellie Simmonds is a Paralympian who won gold medals for swimming at the 2008, 2012 and 2016 Paralympic Games and holds a number of world records. She was the youngest member of the British team at the 2008 Games."},
  {"id":"6735","question":"Each of the UK countries is associated with a flower symbol, which country is associated with the rose?","answers":[{"text":"Wales","correct":false},{"text":"Northern Ireland","correct":false},{"text":"Scotland","correct":false},{"text":"England","correct":true}],"explanation":"The countries that make up the UK all have flowers which are particularly associated with them and which are sometimes worn on national saints’ days. The flowers associated to each country are as follows: England – the rose, Scotland – the thistle, Wales – the daffodil and Northern Ireland – the shamrock."},
  {"id":"6736","question":"Isambard Kingdom Brunel was responsible for:","answers":[{"text":"The construction of the Great Western Railway.","correct":true},{"text":"The invention of the television.","correct":false},{"text":"The construction of the Tower of London.","correct":false},{"text":"The discovery of insulin.","correct":false}],"explanation":"Brunel was originally from Portsmouth, England. He was an engineer who built tunnels, bridges, railway lines and ships. He was responsible for constructing the Great Western Railway, which was the first major railway built in Britain. It runs from Paddington Station in London to the south west of England, the West Midlands and Wales."},
  {"id":"6737","question":"What is the Commonwealth?","answers":[{"text":"An organization responsible for the protection and promotion of human rights in its member countries.","correct":false},{"text":"A group of European and North American countries that have agreed to help each other if they come under attack.","correct":false},{"text":"An association of countries that support each other and work together towards shared goals in democracy and development.","correct":true},{"text":"An international organization that aims to prevent war and promote international peace and security.","correct":false}],"explanation":"The Commonwealth is an association of countries that support each other and work together towards shared goals in democracy and development. Most member states were once part of the British Empire, although a few countries which were not have also joined."},
  {"id":"6738","question":"Under which name was the movement of opinion against the authority of the Pope during the times of Henry VIII known?","answers":[{"text":"The Spanish Inquisition","correct":false},{"text":"The Holy Wars","correct":false},{"text":"The Reformation","correct":true},{"text":"The Enlightenment","correct":false}],"explanation":"The correct answer is the Reformation."},
  {"id":"6739","question":"What did Isaac Newton discover?","answers":[{"text":"Gravity","correct":true},{"text":"Penicillin","correct":false},{"text":"Insulin","correct":false},{"text":"Lightbulb","correct":false}],"explanation":"Newton’s most famous published work was Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica (‘Mathematical Principle of Natural Philosophy’), which showed how gravity applied to the whole universe. Newton also discovered that white light is made up of the colours of the rainbow."},
  {"id":"6740","question":"What kind of movies did Academy Award winner Nick Park specialise in?","answers":[{"text":"Action movies","correct":false},{"text":"Animated movies","correct":true},{"text":"Thrillers","correct":false},{"text":"Horror movies","correct":false}],"explanation":"Britain continues to be particularly strong in special effects and animation. One example is the work of Nick Park, who has won four Oscars for his animated films, including three for films featuring Wallace and Gromit."}
];









